<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[kahvi's blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[I create here sometimes. And rarely capitalize.]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2019 02:45:06 GMT</lastBuildDate><item><title><![CDATA[2019]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’m going into this year feeling good. Mostly because it started exactly on the beat switch in Nights.Few points:Write down thoughts and…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2019-01-02-2019/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2019-01-02-2019/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 02 Jan 2019 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’m going into this year feeling good. Mostly because it started exactly on the beat switch in Nights.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Few points:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write down thoughts and experiences so that I will remember them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Need to start looking at my haircut from a side-on view (tell barber)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop blow-drying hair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do more sober things with friends (cards, movies, day-trips, etc)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Prioritize health&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wake-up early&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Set specific goals to get things done&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try not to slouch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take more chances &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Always be willing to learn&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Go skydiving&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enjoy silence&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;At least 7.5 hours sleep&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cook with rice more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Wear a turtleneck with a blazer to an event&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Drink more water&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Knit&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop watching corny movies instead of good ones&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be grateful&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Happy New Year!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[shortcuts]]></title><description><![CDATA[this post is incompleteSkip to the shortcuts.Disclaimer: I am not expert in this subject, but I’ve done my best to avoid misinformation…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2018-11-22-shortcuts/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2018-11-22-shortcuts/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 22 Nov 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Skip to the &lt;a href=&quot;#shortcuts&quot;&gt;shortcuts&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Disclaimer: I am &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; expert in this subject, but I’ve done my best to avoid misinformation throughout this post. If I’ve gotten anything wrong, send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I’ve gotten better at interacting with my computer.&lt;br&gt;
It’s a mid-2014 MacBook Pro with 8GB of RAM, 128GB of storage; pretty standard. Despite these outdated stats, I don’t want a new computer.
My relationship with my laptop has changed. Even though it’s 5 years old, these days it feels like I’m interacting with a new machine. More accurately, I have a &lt;em&gt;new way&lt;/em&gt; of interacting with my machine. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, this post is all about inputs. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Usually to make your computer do things, you interact with it through a controller. Those controllers are usually a mouse/trackpad and a keyboard.&lt;br&gt;
For the majority of my life, the mouse was the way I interacted with a computer. This means what you think it does. Clicking, dragging, selecting, highlighting; everything was done using my hand to move the mouse across the screen. The keyboard was used for typing, turning up the brightness and maybe pausing Youtube videos.
This method of interaction is fine. It’s cool. It’s what most people do.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It isn’t fast though. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The keyboard is fast. If you are a relatively good typer (like I am), the keyboard will change your life.
Put simply, &lt;strong&gt;I’m telling you to use more keyboard shortcuts.&lt;/strong&gt;
The reason I wrote a whole blog post to tell you this is because it really speeds up &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; you do.
I created this blog post, setup a localhost to view it on Chrome and am writing this post &lt;em&gt;all&lt;/em&gt; without touching the trackpad.
This also implies something important. The less you use the mouse, the less you need a Graphical User Interface (GUI).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is how I think of it. Imagine you have a window on your computer screen with a bunch of buttons on it. Like the toolbar in Microsoft Word. Every button on that screen has a specific function: Set the font size, font colour, line spacing, bold, etc. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/word-toolbar.png&quot; alt=&quot;Word toolbar&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To use these functions, you navigate the mouse to each button. This takes time because you are typing words, then you have to use the mouse, then you have to switch back to using the keyboard. What if you didn’t have to navigate your mouse to anything? What if the keys on your keyboard are the buttons!?
In that case, why have the buttons on the screen in the first place? If the buttons are your keys, why do you need buttons on the screen?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Okay, that was a bit confusing. Let me put this another way.&lt;br&gt;
Imagine you didn’t have a keyboard. Imagine you had to write an essay using a mouse and a virtual keyboard on the screen. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/virtual-keyboard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;virtual keyboard mac&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That would suck, right? Clicking every character? It would take so long! Even though clicking one letter on a virtual keyboard takes less than a second, doing it repeatedly adds up.
This same idea applies to interacting with your computer as a whole. For &lt;em&gt;most&lt;/em&gt; things, the keyboard is faster than the mouse. Individual operations are not faster by hours or minutes or seconds. They’re faster by less than a second. But again, it adds up.
This leads to the command line.
The command line is an application with exactly this in mind. The keyboard is your &lt;em&gt;only&lt;/em&gt; controller. The mouse is useless. Therefore, a GUI is pretty useless too. That’s why you only see characters on the screen and no buttons.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/command-line.png&quot; alt=&quot;command line&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ll come clean though. At first, my motivation to learn how to use the command line was because it looks cool. It looks really cool. Ever seen a hacking scene in a movie where the hacker is moving a mouse to something? No! They’re &lt;strong&gt;typing&lt;/strong&gt; gibberish because &lt;strong&gt;typing&lt;/strong&gt; gibberish is so much faster than clicking gibberish.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Also once you get used to it, it’s really fast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you are a developer or are interesting in coding, the command line becomes a big part of your life.
If not, the command line doesn’t &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; matter &amp;#x3C;- (a claim I’m making).
BUT keyboard shortcuts to navigate your OS do. Since I’m on Mac, this is a list of easy shortcuts I can provide.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Shortcuts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Legend:  
⌘ is the Command key  
⌥ is the Option key  
⇧ is the Shift key
  
“+” means pressing the two keys at the same time

MacOS
- Switch Apps: ⌘ + Tab
- Navigate Workspaces: Control + ← or →
- Search with spotlight: ⌘ + space

Applications 
- New Tab: ⌘ + t
- Type in Nav Bar: ⌘ + l
- Navigate Tabs: ⌘ + ⌥ + ← or →
- Save File: ⌘ + s
- Close Window: ⌘ + w
- Undo: ⌘ + z
- Redo: ⌘ + ⇧ + z
- Zoom In/Out: ⌘ + + or -
- Quit App: ⌘ + q

Text
- Select All: ⌘ + a
- Make Bold: ⌘ + b
- Make Italic: ⌘ + i
- Select Words:  ⌥ + ⇧ +  ← or →
- Navigate Words: ⌥ +  ← or →
~~~
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Volunteer Robot]]></title><description><![CDATA[Over the course of summer 2018, I forked and developed a volunteer scheduling database application. The README  I created builds on the…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2018-09-12-Volunteer Robot/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2018-09-12-Volunteer Robot/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 12 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Over the course of summer 2018, I forked and developed a volunteer scheduling database application. The &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/iamkahvi/volunteers&quot;&gt;README &lt;/a&gt; I created builds on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/playasoft/volunteers&quot;&gt;forked repository&apos;s README&lt;/a&gt; and describes usage, features and installation of the application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post exists to specify which features I developed alone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Table of Content&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#ui-design&quot;&gt;UI Design&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Dashboard&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Event Page&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#backend-features&quot;&gt;Backend Features&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Email Notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hide Empty Days Feature&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filtering Users by Role for admins&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Change to Reminder timing through .ENV laravel doc&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Filter by week&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;UI Design&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Event Page&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I added a legend to the Event page. I changed the text formatting to make the page more legible.
I changed the date format to make the page more legible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/EventCompare.png&quot; alt=&quot;Compare Event&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Dashboard&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Using the bootstrap list items element, I made the dashboard more legible.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/DashboardCompare.png&quot; alt=&quot;Compare Dashboard&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Backend Features&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Email Notifications&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the advice of the original developer, my plan for developing the email notification feature was:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Create a console command which loops through a table for any shifts starting within the next &quot;hour&quot;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If a volunteer has signed up for that slot, send them a notification&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add value to SQL table to prevent further notifications&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Add the command to the Laravel cron so it runs periodically (every 5 minutes? 15 minutes?)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This approach was somewhat inefficient given the Laravel cron would be running continuously when it wouldn&apos;t need to. Scheduling a task immediately when a user signs up instead of iterating through the table continuously would be a better approach. Ultimately I chose to implement the feature as a simple solution using the existing schema as opposed to changing the schema and the controller logic.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To work through the logic of when to send reminders, I create variables for when the shift starts and when to remind the user for that specific
shift. I do this by creating two &lt;a href=&quot;https://carbon.nesbot.com/docs/&quot;&gt;Carbon&lt;/a&gt; dates and add a user-designated amount of hours to the second variable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-php&quot;&gt;&amp;#x3C;?php

// Cycle through all the slots
foreach($shifts as $shift)
{
    $startDate = new Carbon(date(&apos;Y-m-d H:i:s&apos;, strtotime(&quot;$shift-&gt;start_date $shift-&gt;start_time&quot;)));

    $remindDate = new Carbon(date(&apos;Y-m-d H:i:s&apos;, strtotime(&quot;$shift-&gt;start_date $shift-&gt;start_time&quot;)));

    $now = Carbon::now();

    $remindDate-&gt;subHours(env(&apos;REMIND_HOURS&apos;));
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find the shift starting within the given reminder period using the variables.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-php&quot;&gt;&amp;#x3C;?php
if($remindDate &amp;#x3C;= $now and $startDate &gt; $now)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then, I cycle through all users to find who is registered for the shift in question.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-php&quot;&gt;&amp;#x3C;?php
foreach ($users as $user)
    {
        // Find user that is registered for this shift
        if ($user-&gt;id == $shift-&gt;user_id) {
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then I notify the user of the shift. I used the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.mailgun.com/email-api&quot;&gt;MailGun api&lt;/a&gt; with &lt;a href=&quot;https://laravel.com/docs/5.2/mail&quot;&gt;Laravel&lt;/a&gt; to send the emails.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-php&quot;&gt;&amp;#x3C;?php           
// Notify user of upcoming shift
if($shift-&gt;isNotified == &apos;No&apos;)
{
    $user-&gt;notify(new shiftStarting($shift, $user));
} else
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In order to prevent the user from getting continuously notified, I created a column in the shifts table to track notification status.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-php&quot;&gt;&amp;#x3C;?php

// Update isNotified value in SQL database
DB::table(&apos;slots&apos;)
    -&gt;where(&apos;id&apos;, $shift-&gt;id)
    -&gt;update([&apos;isNotified&apos; =&gt; &apos;Yes&apos;]);
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Hide Empty Days Feature&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Volunteer Robot often displayed days on the event page which didn&apos;t contain any shifts. This meant a lot of unecessary scrolling for users.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My strategy was to cycle through each day that would be displayed on the event page and check if the day had a shift.
Fortunately, this check was relatively simple after looking into different SQL queries.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-php&quot;&gt;&amp;#x3C;?php
// Pluck all of the shift IDs for this event and check the if any in the schedule start today
if(Schedule::whereIn(&apos;shift_id&apos;, $shifts)-&gt;where(&apos;dates&apos;, &apos;LIKE&apos;, &quot;%&quot;.$date-&gt;format(&apos;Y-m-d&apos;).&quot;%&quot;)-&gt;get()-&gt;isEmpty())
{
// Continue onto the next day
$date-&gt;addDay();
continue;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Filtering Users by Role for admins&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The admins of the Volunteer Robot regularly send out mass emails to volunteers according to their &quot;Role&quot;. They wanted to filter the users by their Role in order to access email addresses more efficiently.   &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I wanted to work in plain javascript for this feature to familiarize myself. This feature was challenging because the Users, Roles, and User Roles are all located in seperate SQL tables. Thankfully, this issue was easy to deal with once I understood how to make SQL queries within blade.php files. I plucked each user&apos;s roles from the User Role table and put it in a class attribute.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/FilterUsersHTML.png&quot; alt=&quot;Filer Users HTML&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;On the other end, my main concern was how to filter users with multiple roles. Since my query returned a string of text, there was no way to distinguish one role from another. I had to split the result of that query in javascript to make it an array of each role. Then it was much easier to find out if the specified user had that role in their respective array.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt; $(&apos;.filter-user-roles&apos;).on(&apos;change&apos;, function () {
       
        // define the role
        var role = $(&quot;.filter-user-roles&quot;).val();

        // define all the spans of the users
        var users = document.querySelectorAll(&apos;.email-block .user-block&apos;);

        // hide all the users
        users.forEach(function(element) {
            element.style.display = &quot;none&quot;;
        });

        if (role == &quot;all&quot;) {
            
            // show all users
            users.forEach(function(element) {
                element.style.display = &quot;inline&quot;;
            });
        
        } else {

            // show user if they have that role
            users.forEach(function(user) {

                var userRoles = user.getAttribute(&apos;data-role&apos;).slice(1,-1).split(&quot;,&quot;);

                if (userRoles.includes(role)) {
                    user.style.display = &quot;inline&quot;;
                }
            })

        }
    });
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Filter by week&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fortunately, there existed an implementation of a feature similar to this one in the application. This made it much easier to work this one out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-javascript&quot;&gt;// Hide all the days
$(&apos;.days .day&apos;).addClass(&apos;hidden&apos;);

// Convert date to Moment format
let m = moment();

m = moment(date.toString());

// Show this one

// Loop through seven days
for(var i = 0; i &amp;#x3C; 7; i++)
{
    $(&apos;.days .day[data-date=&quot;&apos; + m.format(&apos;Y-MM-DD&apos;) + &apos;&quot;]&apos;).removeClass(&apos;hidden&apos;);
    $(window).trigger(&apos;resize&apos;);
    m.add(1, &apos;days&apos;);
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The most challenging part of implementing this feature was installing the Moment package on the active server. Without this package, I wasn&apos;t able to manipulate date strings easily.
Since the server ran Ubuntu, the package wouldn&apos;t install. After some Googling, one line of code in the header.blade.php solved all my problems.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-html&quot;&gt; &amp;#x3C;script src=&quot;https://cdn.jsdelivr.net/npm/moment@2.22.2/moment.min.js&quot;&gt;&amp;#x3C;/script&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[position paper]]></title><description><![CDATA[I’ve been going through old papers of mine recently and this one struck me as interesting enough to share. I wrote a barebones post on this…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2018-09-10-position paper/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2018-09-10-position paper/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been going through old papers of mine recently and this one struck me as interesting enough to share. I wrote a barebones &lt;a href=&quot;%7B%25%20post_url%202017-11-03-on-behavioural-economics%20%25%7D&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on this subject.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kahvi Patel&lt;br&gt;
Research Paper&lt;br&gt;
April 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2017
{: .academic}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt; In the early 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century, the separation between scientific and non-scientific theories was vague. The most practical way to distinguish a theory as scientific was to determine whether it was known a posteriori; relied on an empirical method. This meant that astrology, given its vast amounts of observed information, qualified as a scientific theory. In 1919, Karl Popper sought to contrive an alternative separation. Falsifiability was the philosophical term he coined. With this theory, Popper set the groundwork for the modern scientific method and, simultaneously, addressed the problem of induction that had troubled Hume and many other philosophers before him. Popper’s theory of Demarcation not only has its roots in philosophy, but in human nature. As has been the case throughout history, human nature is more prone towards what Popper distinguished as “pseudo-scientific” theories rather than “scientific” ones. Our inherent desires are what make Popper’s theory of Falsification especially relevant; Demarcation is a tool to fight against our own misleading instincts. In order to repress this widespread malpractice, we must employ tactics of doubt exemplified by philosophers like Descartes and Socrates in order to enforce a more logical, and therefore more productive, general consciousness. As Popper originally described in his theory, &lt;em&gt;we must seek falsification&lt;/em&gt;, or doubt, &lt;em&gt;rather than confirmation&lt;/em&gt; in order to prove our own theories.
{: .academic .indent}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Popper, the reason for distinguishing between theories was not “ doubting the &lt;em&gt;truth&lt;/em&gt; of those other theories, but something else” (Popper 32). What bothered Popper were the incessant “confirming instances” relating to the “pseudo-scientific theories” in question. Freud’s theory of psychoanalysis, for example, was supported repeatedly by whatever the psychologist theorized. In other words, &lt;em&gt;every event confirmed the theory&lt;/em&gt;. This practice has a flaw.
{: .academic .indent}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I may illustrate this by two very different examples of human behavior: that of a man who pushes a child into the water with the intention of drowning it; and that of a man who sacrifices his life in an attempt to save the child. Each of these two cases can be explained with equal ease in Freudian and in Adlerian terms. According to Freud the first man suffered from repression (say, of some component of his Oedipus complex), while the second man had achieved sublimation. According to Adler the first man suffered from feelings of inferiority (producing perhaps the need to prove to himself that he dared to commit some crime), and so did the second man (whose need was to prove to himself that he dared to rescue the child). (Popper 35)&lt;/p&gt;
{: .academic}
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This situation demonstrates the ambiguity of Freud’s (and Adler’s) theory. The result, no matter how unexpected or crazy, can always be justified. This method was in direct contrast to another Popper had witnessed; Einstein&apos;s theory of gravitation. Whereas Freud’s theory relied on explanation, Einstein’s relied on prediction. More specifically, one sought &lt;em&gt;confirmation&lt;/em&gt;, the other sought &lt;em&gt;falsification&lt;/em&gt;. Alarmingly though, both relied on empirical evidence and the method of induction, thus classing them both, for now, as scientific theories. Importantly, Popper did not attempt to discredit the validity of Freud’s theory, although he may have done so unconsciously. His intention was merely to distinguish it. The significance of this separation cannot be understated. As history progressed, a scientific method was developed around Popper’s falsifiability and a separation began to emerge between science and others things.
{: .academic}&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than just a method for distinction between theories, Falsification has significance in human behavior. In general, humans are programmed to ignore events that do not agree with their beliefs and pay attentions to ones that do. This behavior is called &lt;em&gt;confirmation bias&lt;/em&gt; and has been proven to exist in many studies, the most famous of which is the Wason Selection Task. Feel free to attempt this experiment on friends.&lt;/p&gt;
{: .academic .indent}
&gt; &lt;p&gt;He presented subjects with the three-number sequence 2, 4, 6, and asked them to try and guess the rule generating it. Their method of guessing was to produce other three-number sequences, to which the experimenter would respond &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; depending on whether the new sequences were consistent with the rule. Once confident with their answers, the subjects would formulate the rule. The correct rule was &amp;ldquo;numbers in ascending order,&amp;rdquo; nothing more. Very few subjects discovered it because in order to do so they had to offer a series in descending order (that the experimenter would say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to). (Taleb 123)&lt;/p&gt;{: .academic}
&lt;p&gt;This experiment demonstrates our inherent instinct to always seek confirmation for our own hypothesis, or theories, instead or trying to discredit them. Once the subjects had formulated a rule, their only intention became trying to find a pattern that fit it instead of trying to supply a series that was &lt;em&gt;inconsistent&lt;/em&gt; with their hypothesis. Our natural human behavior compels us to seek confirmation. The parallels here are widespread. Today, most people gather their information (and biases) from the news and there is more news today than ever before. The constant news cycle compounds biases. People have access to countless sources of evidence, or &quot;number series&quot;, which they use to confirm their own opinions. It becomes much more difficult to attempt to disprove your own opinion.&lt;/p&gt;
{: .academic}
&lt;p&gt;A most poignant example of this behavior of confirmation bias is the political polarization that currently exists in the United States: both sides seek confirmation for their own theories, never falsification. Popper&amp;rsquo;s Demarcation seems to work against human instinct. For instance, Freud&amp;rsquo;s theory of psychoanalysis is more easily understandable than Einstein&amp;rsquo;s theory of gravity and thus more attractive. This inherent preference leads to many human patterns of behavior, such as illusion of control and hindsight bias. When a need to explain something arises, we are predisposed to justify our theory by seeking confirmation instead of testing it. A striking example of this behavior is the justification for the start of World War 1. Clearly, the assassination of Franz Ferdinand and the escalating tension and militarization in various countries might predict international conflict. The ensuing World War seems to have been &lt;em&gt;inevitable&lt;/em&gt; - after the events have transpired. This is an example of hindsight bias. As Niall Ferguson, a professor of history at Harvard, makes clear in his paper &lt;em&gt;The international bond market between the 1848 revolution and the outbreak of the First World War&lt;/em&gt;, the world had not noticed these so-called significant events, as evidenced by the flat lining of war bond prices. &lt;strong&gt;If these hints towards the upcoming conflict were as clear as we now make them out to be, why did the price of war bonds not rise? &lt;/strong&gt;Was there a sudden, universal lack of desire to make profit? or were the events we speak of today &lt;em&gt;not obvious at all&lt;/em&gt;. Clearly, the latter is more in line with human nature. The pseudo-scientific theory suggests that the war started because of an episode of tension and militarization. We feel the need to justify events after the fact in order to reassure ourselves that we will see it coming next time. Yet, until those theories in question can withstand falsification, this practice of explanation is useless.&lt;/p&gt;
{: .academic .indent}
&lt;p&gt;When theories are not tested with falsification, they can lead us to misleading conclusions or a false sense of security. In 470 BC, Socrates exposed society&amp;rsquo;s wrongful act of gathering, spreading and reciting knowledge that had illogical grounds. In what we now call &amp;ldquo;Socratic Dialogue&amp;rdquo;, Socrates reduced his subject&amp;rsquo;s opinions to a single thesis which was often illogical. Through this, he proved the Delphi&amp;rsquo;s prophecy true: he was, in fact, &amp;ldquo;the wisest of men&amp;rdquo;. This title, however, did not originate from vast education or far-reaching experience.&lt;/p&gt;{: .academic .indent}
&gt; &lt;p&gt;I am wiser than this man; it is likely that neither of us knows anything worthwhile, but he thinks he knows something when he does not, whereas when I do not know, neither do I think I know; so I am likely to be wiser than he to this small extent, that &lt;em&gt;I do not think I know what I do not know&lt;/em&gt;. (Plato 3)&lt;/p&gt;{: .academic}
&lt;p&gt;Socrates was merely the only man who knew the extent of his own ignorance. Today, we encounter a similar situation. Many of our generally accepted theories and personal opinions are illogical and/or justified by a flawed method. More importantly though, the vast majority of society &lt;em&gt;does not realize&lt;/em&gt; this. Descartes provides another apt exemplar. His doubt, though undoubtedly extreme, was important to build a foundation of truth upon which the rest of his beliefs were founded.&lt;/p&gt;{: .academic}
&gt; &lt;p&gt;It is as though they [my beliefs] had a right to a place in my belief-system as a result of long occupation and the law of custom. These habitual opinions of mine are indeed highly probable; although they are in a sense doubtful, as I have shown, it is more reasonable to believe than to deny them. But if I go on viewing them in that light I shall never get out of the habit of confidently assenting to them. To conquer that habit, therefore, I had better switch right around and pretend (for a while) that these former opinions of mine are utterly false and imaginary. I shall do this until I have something to counter-balance the weight of old opinion, and the distorting influence of habit no longer prevents me from judging correctly. (Descartes 2)&lt;/p&gt;{: .academic}
&lt;p&gt;The important parallel here is doubt. To doubt one&amp;rsquo;s own belief is the most basic and true form of falsification. We must take advice from Socrates and Descartes and question our own theories and opinions in order to arrive at the roots of our beliefs. We must acknowledge our own ignorance in order to take the next step towards progress.&lt;/p&gt;{: .academic}
&lt;p&gt;Popper&amp;rsquo;s philosophy was originally meant to distinguish scientific theories. His philosophy of Demarcation, however, went beyond science, and addressed two methods of thinking. Unfortunately for humanity, we are prone to the less reliable mode of thinking: one that seeks confirmation. This behavior has led to a worrying trend in human history. By analyzing the past and present, we may understand how hindsight bias and the illusion of control reveal themselves in society and how they are the result of instinctual human behavior. With the problem assessed and recognized, we may understand it and endeavor to solve it. Doubt is perhaps the truest form of falsification and should be practiced by individuals today in order to justify beliefs. Unless we begin challenging our beliefs, instead of seeking confirmation of them, progress of all kinds will slow.&lt;/p&gt;{: .academic .indent}
&lt;br&gt;
Works Cited
{: .academic}
- Popper, Karl. &lt;em&gt;Conjectures and Refutations&lt;/em&gt;. Basic Books, 1962. &lt;br&gt;
- Nicholas Taleb, Nassim. &lt;em&gt;The Black Swan: The Impact of the Highly
- Improbable.&lt;/em&gt; Random House, 2007.&lt;br&gt;
- Ferguson, Niall. &amp;ldquo;Political risk and the international bond market between the 1848 revolution and the outbreak of the First World War.&amp;rdquo; &lt;em&gt;Economic History Review&lt;/em&gt;, Vol 29, no. 1, February 2006.&lt;br&gt;
- Plato. &lt;em&gt;Apology&lt;/em&gt;. translated by G.M.A. Grube, Hackett Publishing Company, 2000.&lt;br&gt;
- Descartes, Renee. &lt;em&gt;Meditations on First Philosophy&lt;/em&gt;. translated by Jonathan&amp;nbsp;F.&amp;nbsp;Bennett, Cambridge University Press, 1996.&lt;br&gt;
{: .academic}</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[R for Loving Spoonful]]></title><description><![CDATA[I made some apps with Shiny and R to visualize the data gathered with several programs that were implemented last year.The first app{:target…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2018-09-09-R for Loving Spoonful/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2018-09-09-R for Loving Spoonful/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I made some apps with Shiny and R to visualize the data gathered with several programs that were implemented last year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;https://lovingspoonful.shinyapps.io/app1/&quot;&gt;first app&lt;/a&gt;{:target=&quot;blank&quot;} I created to give an easy overview of the food reclamation growth over the course of 12 months. This would help anticipate trends to prepare more effectively for the next year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After that, I used data from a collection program I help implement in the summer of 2017 to give a helpful visualization of what kinds of food were donated most often and at what frequency. This &lt;a href=&quot;https://lovingspoonful.shinyapps.io/app2/&quot;&gt;app &lt;/a&gt;{:target=&quot;blank&quot;} is here.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[my youtube channel]]></title><description><![CDATA[I have a youtube channel.It's been fun posting videos. A more involved form of self-expression than instagram.I have ones about sailing…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2018-07-21-youtube/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2018-07-21-youtube/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/techkid105&quot;&gt;youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&apos;s been fun posting videos. A more involved form of self-expression than instagram.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have ones about &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/yli2zN2mV4M&quot;&gt;sailing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/_Bn3N3SI2-o&quot;&gt;skiing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/4acqZOnjB70&quot;&gt;skating&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/ftmrS3Eg2-I&quot;&gt;skating&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/8iYcGz_nrj8&quot;&gt;scrambled eggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&apos;m only now realizing the alliteration.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One lesson learned: &lt;strong&gt;the edit is all that matters&lt;/strong&gt;. For me, 90% of the effort is put in during the edit.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[us ideology]]></title><description><![CDATA[This one gets into political ideology which I don't usually like to talk about.
Spending a few days in and around Chicago has illustrated to…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//drafts/X2018-07-21-us ideology/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//drafts/X2018-07-21-us ideology/</guid><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;This one gets into political ideology which I don&apos;t usually like to talk about.
Spending a few days in and around Chicago has illustrated to me the constant, uncomfortable tension in American society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To begin, Canada is not that different from America. Obviously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If money is our objective measure of success, Canada is failing. Our dollar is weaker. Is the mentality behind the US economy the right one? So often it&apos;s painted as an abstract idea of perseverance and determination over everything. Seeing this in effect is less simple.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We use money as our objective measure of success because that&apos;s what everyone else uses.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The stress I see around Chicago is not unlike the one that exists in Kingston. There are wealthy areas and not wealth areas. What disturbs me is the scale to which this applies in America. It&apos;s either poor or rich.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I read this in every headline: The middle class is disappearing. It&apos;s really harsh to see the reality reflect those headlines.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Everything that&apos;s big is bigger. Everything that&apos;s small is smaller. Everyone that&apos;s rich is richer, everyone that&apos;s poor is poorer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(This is me dumming an incredible complex issue down to an easily digestible couple sentences that sound the same to make it easier to convince you of my perspective)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But the difficulty is that people want it that way. The mentality is all or nothing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You wonder why so many people fall into that trap of inflated optimism. I&apos;m a victim to it. I think my future will be brighter than it should be. It&apos;s a country of idealists. With no facts to go around. And their infrastructure is shitty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The mentality is confusing. For there to be winners, there have to be losers. Yet the losers think they&apos;re all winners in the making and the winners keep convincing reinforcing that false belief.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[on gladwell]]></title><description><![CDATA[Background: Malcolm Gladwell hosts a podcast, he did an episode on CTE today. Chronic traumatic encephalopathy (CTE) is the reason everyone…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2018-05-28-on gladwell/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2018-05-28-on gladwell/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Background: Malcolm Gladwell hosts a &lt;a href=&quot;http://revisionisthistory.com/seasons?selected=season-3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;, he did an episode on CTE today. Chronic traumatic encephalopathy (CTE) is the reason everyone is scared of football these days: Head trauma leads a bunch of bad stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;His thesis, basically, is: “At what point do you have enough proof to act?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In a speech given at UPenn in 2013, Gladwell uses the example of coal miners in the 1940s. Coal was an integral part of the economy back then; many working class families were supported by the industry. There were drawbacks though. Namely, workers would cough up black coal dust and generally cough a lot. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For various reasons, people said the coughing was a sign of the respiratory system working &lt;em&gt;correctly&lt;/em&gt; and did not consider negative health impacts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then a statistician came along and &lt;strong&gt;proved&lt;/strong&gt; that inhaling coal dust all day was very bad for you and reduces your life expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, in his speech, Malcolm asks the audience “What do you think happened then?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Nothing&lt;/em&gt;” he answers dramatically (it was a rhetorical question).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until 1975 that a general consensus was reached about the dangers of coal mining and action was taken. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gladwell’s parallel is with football today.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;He goes on to argue that the students at UPenn should boycott the school’s football game in protest of the University ignoring proof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have a problem with his argument though.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If an adult is aware of the risks of an activity and is not harming others in the process, what right do we have to stop them?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This question has little to do with football, yet is the core of Gladwell’s argument. &lt;em&gt;Every sport&lt;/em&gt; has different degrees of good and bad depending on who you ask.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The key insight is that the people participating should be the ones to weigh the pros and cons, not us. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Society should do everything in its power to provide information to judge the sport with (like studies about CTE), but the &lt;em&gt;decisions made&lt;/em&gt; based on that information are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in society’s control.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea of athletes taking this decision into their own hands was never addressed in the podcast. Instead, athletes were only mentioned when the consequences of &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; actions befell &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Malcolm strays away from this moral question, or purposefully ignores it, because it is harder to answer than the one he asks in his podcast.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reducing this issue down to right and wrong is reductive and demeans the judgment of football players/responsible adults.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[on statistics]]></title><description><![CDATA[Naked Statisticssidenote: This post is based entirely on what I've learned while reading ^that book.Three concepts in statistics that are…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2018-05-09-on statistics/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2018-05-09-on statistics/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Naked-Statistics-Stripping-Dread-Data/dp/1480590185&quot;&gt;Naked Statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sidenote: &lt;em&gt;This post is based entirely on what I&apos;ve learned while reading ^that book.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Three concepts in statistics that are important to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;1. Law of Large Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“An important theorem known as the law of large numbers tells us that as the number of trials increases, the average of the outcomes will get closer and closer to its expected value”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is counter intuitive. This is how I think of this theory.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You are flipping a coin 10 times. Imagine the first eight times you flip the coin, it lands on heads. Intuitively, you would assume that the next flip is more likely to land on tails than heads. This is FALSE.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time you flip the coin, nothing different is happening. Every flip is a 50/50 chance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of your 10 flips, you have landed nine heads and one tail. This doesn’t make sense. If the likelihood of flipping both possibilities is equal, why is the outcome so skewed?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is because you have witnessed an anomaly. The chances of you hitting nine heads in a row are very small (1/512 or 0.2%). The results you have witnessed are not representative of the true probability.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The true probability only emerges as you keep flipping the coin.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The logic behind this is hard to understand.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Basically, the more time you flip the coin, the less anomalies (like nine heads in a row) will matter to the overall result. Eventually anomalies are drowned out and the true probability can be seen.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The chart below illustrates the theory. Every flip, the average of heads is calculated: (number of head flips / total number of flips). According to everything that makes sense, that number should be 0.5 or 1/2.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/heads14.png&quot; alt=&quot;Coin Flip Chart&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the first 10 trials, the average number of heads fluctuates wildly, from an underrepresentation to an overrepresentation in 10 flips. You can see how if we stopped after just 10 flips, it would be hard to draw a conclusion about the &lt;em&gt;true probability&lt;/em&gt; of this situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As more coins are flipped though, the average number of heads move closer to 0.5, which is what probability says it should be.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The law of large numbers explains why casinos always make money in the long run. The probabilities associated with all casino games favor the house (assuming that the casino can successfully prevent blackjack players from counting cards). If enough bets are wagered over a long enough time, the casino will be certain to win more than it loses.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wheelan, Charles. “Naked Statistics: Stripping the Dread from the Data.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;2. Independent and Dependent Relations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time a coin is flipped heads, the chance of the second flip being heads stays exactly the same. This is called an independent relation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every time a car is parked, the chance of the driver getting a parking ticket increases. This is a dependent relation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Often, we do not realize what event are independent and dependent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The classic example is a “hot-hand” in basketball. After a player makes a certain amount of shots in a row, it seems more likely that he will make the next shot. We assume that this is a dependent relation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0010028585900106&quot;&gt;It isn’t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;3. Percentages&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More often than not, a percentage is a better way to understand data than an absolute number.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking at a storefront, I would rather know what &lt;em&gt;percentage&lt;/em&gt; of the price is discounted than an absolute number. Saving $5 on a $10 item is awesome, but saving $5 on a $2000 item is almost irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When looking at a company, I would rather know a &lt;em&gt;percentage&lt;/em&gt; for revenue growth rather than an absolute number. Growing yearly revenues from $20 billion to $20.1 billion is not a huge difference, but $100 million in additional revenue &lt;em&gt;sounds&lt;/em&gt; great.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Percentages give you context for absolute numbers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Therefore, we should address some fallacies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;1.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Assume that a department store is selling a dress for $100. The assistant manager marks down all merchandise by 25 percent. But then that assistant manager is fired…and the new assistant manager raises all prices by 25 percent. What is the final price of the dress? If you said (or thought) $100, ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then you are wrong. Here is what happened.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The price was originally $100. Then it was discounted by 25%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25% of $100 is, clearly, $25. Therefore, the new price is $100 - $25 = $75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Then the price was raised by 25%.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;25% of $75 is $18.75. Therefore, the new price is $75 + $18.75 = $93.75.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This concept is especially important in the stock market:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Say you buy $50 of Apple stock on Monday. The stock goes down 12% on Tuesday, but then goes up 12% on Wednesday. You do not start Thursday with $50 of Apple stock. You will have less.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;2.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The Democrats, who engineered this tax increase, pointed out (correctly) that the state income tax rate was increased by 2 percentage points (from 3 percent to 5 percent). The Republicans pointed out (also correctly) that the state income tax had been raised by 67 percent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This example&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.479.3099&amp;#x26;rep=rep1&amp;#x26;type=pdf&quot;&gt;Luck versus Skill in the Cross-Section of Mutual Fund Returns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[A Gentleman In Moscow]]></title><description><![CDATA[A Gentleman in Moscow
by Amor Towles Summary: A Gentleman In Moscow revolves around the romantic idea of a perfect gentleman and a splendid…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2018-01-22-A-Gentleman-In-Moscow/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2018-01-22-A-Gentleman-In-Moscow/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Gentleman in Moscow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
by Amor Towles&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;u&gt; Summary: &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A Gentleman In Moscow revolves around the romantic idea of a perfect gentleman and a splendid hotel. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book begins with a description of your classic idea of a gentleman; tall, well-mannered, polite, gracious. Age: about 40? &lt;br&gt;
After the Bolshevik revolution, he is forced to move out of his suite in the hotel in which he has been living for the past 10 years (?). The Count is relocated in a smaller room on a lower floor and is placed under house arrest. From this day forward, he cannot leave the hotel. &lt;br&gt;
There are various descriptions of the important locations and characters in the hotel: Emile, the chef; Andrey, the maitre’d. &lt;br&gt;
Over the course of his time at the hotel the Count meets many new people, who eventually all play an important role later in his life. &lt;br&gt;
Foremost among those people is Nina whom the Count meets when Nina is 6? They develop a friendship and over the years become close confidants as they explore the hotel together. Nina eventually leaves the hotel with her family. &lt;br&gt;
The Count remains at the hotel, striking up an affair with a movie star, Anna, and developing more familiar relationships with the staff of the hotel various sub-businesses; restaurant, bar, barbershop, tailor, etc. He almost commits suicide but is convinced (indirectly) by a blind man he had made friends with not to. &lt;br&gt;
Many years later, Nina returns to the hotel with her child, Sophia, age six. Nina tells the Count that she must leave for Serbia to find her husband who has gone missing. She implores the Count to take Sophia for what she imagines will only be two or three weeks. &lt;br&gt;
Sophia remains under the care of the Count for much longer than that. Sophia begins referring to the Count as “papa” and their relationship develops from something polite and cold to a warm and loving relationship. &lt;br&gt;
Sophia grows into a smart, driven, beautiful young woman and eventually leaves the hotel to perform with the Moscow Orchestra (she has become an accomplished pianist). The Orchestra performs in Paris and while she is there, Sophia escapes to the American Embassy (under the specific direction of her and the Count’s plan) to meet with another one of the Count’s acquaintances become friend, Richard, who is the American Ambassador to France (?). &lt;br&gt;
The book ends with the Count escaping the hotel after saying goodbye to all his friends there and returning to his childhood town. &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;&lt;u&gt; My takeaways &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book helps the reader to appreciate the culture and history of Russia.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The book argues that a gentleman remains a gentleman no matter their nation of heritage.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It offers an interesting perspective on the passage of time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many life lessons are delivered. This is one of the easier to quote ones:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“ The first was that if one did not master one’s circumstances, one was bound to be mastered by them; and the second was Montaigne’s maxim that the surest sign of wisdom is constant cheerfulness. ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[thoughts on 2017]]></title><description><![CDATA[I don’t really know what to think about 2017.These are a bunch of thoughts that have nothing to do with the new year.I’ve been thinking…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2018-01-01-thoughts-on-2017/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2018-01-01-thoughts-on-2017/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I don’t really know what to think about 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are a bunch of thoughts that have nothing to do with the new year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about education and what the value of a degree is, and the following seems relevant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;u&gt;From David Foster Wallace’s Kenyon College Commencement Speech&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here is the real, no bullshit value of your liberal arts education is supposed to be about: how to keep from going through your comfortable, prosperous, respectable adult life dead, unconscious, a slave to your head and to your natural default setting of being uniquely, completely, imperially alone day in and day out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you worship money and things, if they are where you tap real meaning in life, then you will never have enough, never feel you have enough. It&apos;s the truth. Worship your body and beauty and sexual allure and you will always feel ugly. And when time and age start showing, you will die a million deaths before they finally grieve you. On one level, we all know this stuff already. It&apos;s been codified as myths, proverbs, clichés, epigrams, parables; the skeleton of every great story. The whole trick is keeping the truth up front in daily consciousness. Worship power, you will end up feeling weak and afraid, and you will need ever more power over others to numb you to your own fear. Worship your intellect, being seen as smart, you will end up feeling stupid, a fraud, always on the verge of being found out. But the insidious thing about these forms of worship is not that they&apos;re evil or sinful, it&apos;s that they&apos;re unconscious. They are default settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe that relates to my next point.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;u&gt;Are you day trading? (From Seth Godin’s Blog)&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The volatility of bitcoin turns the people who own it into addicts. At any given moment, it&apos;s up $100 or down a thousand.&lt;br&gt;
When it&apos;s up, you think you&apos;re brilliant, that you somehow had something to do with it.
And when it&apos;s down, the world is about to implode.&lt;br&gt;
Most people don&apos;t day trade bitcoin, but all of us day trade something. We&apos;re hooked into something volatile, easily measured and emotional. We overdo our response to news, good or bad, and let it distract us from the long-term job of living a useful life.&lt;br&gt;
Your SEO results, your Facebook likes, the look on your boss&apos;s face when she gets back from a meeting--all of these things are rife with opportunities for day trading.&lt;br&gt;
It&apos;ll be volatile with or without your help. Better to set it aside and get back to the real work of making a difference instead. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt; This is a rant :&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The goal of a business is to make a profit. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A business employs people because they do work and make the business profitable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You work towards a University degree because you will do work better and will be more attractive to businesses. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, all that matters is &lt;i&gt;results&lt;/i&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s the point. Instead of proving your value through getting a degree, prove your value by getting results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Get page views, get purchase orders, show your understanding of how consumers think and how to take advantage of it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are very few people who teach at Universities who have attained results. They have been taught about results, they talk about results, they think about results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But they never get results. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, the only way to absolutely prove you get results, is to get results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is why I am so unsure of this University thing. No one can prove they know how to get results by teaching. Only by doing. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Summary: Success in University does not directly translate to success in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Finally, &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;u&gt;Creative people have a weird job&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Do you create things that &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; think are cool, or do you create things that you think &lt;em&gt;other people&lt;/em&gt; will like. In more abstract terms, it’s the difference between staying true to yourself and selling out, right? But how do you define the line between your audience’s taste and your own. Presumably, a great creator would accumulate such a unique audience that there would be no difference between their two tastes. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s a matter of having a constant conversation with your audience. Each party challenging the other the create new and better things. The difference between that and losing your own say in the things you create is a blurry one. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I assume the only absolute solution is to create as if your audience is irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Breakfast at Tiffany’s]]></title><description><![CDATA[this post is incompleteother than the blatant racism and subtle sexism, breakfast at tiffany’s is a film that spoke to me. i haven’t had…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2017-12-27-breakfast-at-tiffany&apos;s/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2017-12-27-breakfast-at-tiffany&apos;s/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;other than the blatant racism and subtle sexism, breakfast at tiffany’s is a film that spoke to me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i haven’t had much experience with relationships, but I’ve often come across women who have an almost identical nature as audrey hepburn’s character did in the movie. free-spirited, wild, not normal. the moment things got regular, they force change. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i admire that quality. at this point in my life, i loathe routine even though i live by it for the most part. as often as i can, i try to break patterns and try new things, although it is usually motivated by interest and not to force change for the sake of change.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;certainly, living the way audrey’s character does has a undeniable romantic appeal. those few people i encounter who drift into my life and astonish me only to vanish just as quickly are impossible not to admire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the way connections are made which seem deep on one side, but superficial on another is frightening. i think its every persons fear that a friendship isn’t reciprocated with the same enthusiasm on the other end. in Aubrey’s case, it seems like that fear always comes to fruition.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i guess it isn’t really her fault. the fact that her life is spent quickly building relationships then moving upwards from them may not be her fault. i think the movie makes it out to be her personality and not malicious intent. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the idea of entering someone’s life, astonishing them, then leaving just as quickly is interesting to me. not only for the result on my own life, but also the lasting impression it would leave on said person. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;efficient is another way to look at this. in the most optimistic sense, audrey’s character is getting everything out of a relationship in a short amount of time instead of a long one.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;or maybe the truth is entirely different. just because a person astonishes and surprises you, does not mean that the resulting relationship was “deep”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;presumably, a deep relationship comes from length and not intensity.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;maybe that is the crux of the movie.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;for her whole life, aubrey’s character lived intense and short relationships which is a admirable lifestyle as perceived from the outside. admirable because passion is more easily noticed than depth. by the end of the movie though, she decides to do the opposite and develop a long and perhaps less intense relationship.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;although, i am implying a trade-off here. passionate/exciting relationships are short and “deep” ones are long.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;both of these claims are probably not entirely true. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a deep connection can come out of a short encounter.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the other side i am not so sure.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Age of Ambition]]></title><description><![CDATA[Age of Ambition: Chasing Fortune, Truth, and Faith in the New China
by Evan Osnos Summary: Most books I read don’t stay with me for long…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2017-12-12-Age of Ambition/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2017-12-12-Age of Ambition/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Age of Ambition: Chasing Fortune, Truth, and Faith in the New China&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
by Evan Osnos&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;&lt;u&gt; Summary: &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Most books I read don’t stay with me for long. This one is no different.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
To combat my failing memory, I read this book on a Kindle and highlighted things so that I might remember the entire book in more detail. This post is my attempt at summarizing the book using those highlighted quotations.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
China has always been a mystery to me. The variety of culture found in the United States is so broad that I find trouble believing the one-dimensional image I have in my head of China. A country with arguably the most important economy yet I have not idea how it’s run, it’s history, the source of its growth, etc.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Also, the idea that they’re a communist country? Doesn’t the West hate Commies? Why are we okay with this?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book was easy to read for a couple reasons. First, it is an interesting introduction to a country I know nothing about. It follows personal journeys of people instead of talking about numbers and economics and boring.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Second, it is somewhat reassuring. Here’s a fact that has consistently stuck in my mind: There are more MBAs graduating every year in China than there are undergrads graduating in the US. That’s ridiculous. Especially when there is this pessimistic outlook on the job market. China is a terrifying competitor, compounded by the fact that the US President is practically handing them the role of international leadership.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
That is the interesting part of this book. You are presented with their insane economic success but also China’s flaws and the negative aspect of their ridiculous growth. Notably how there entire society is more “controlled”. It often seems like a Black Mirror episode. &lt;strong&gt;China spends more money on domestic security than national defence&lt;/strong&gt;. Bus routes get rerouted so citizens won’t pass the courthouse when contested cases are in session. Creepy stuff. My optimism comes from the fact that the West has freedom and China doesn’t. That inevitably changes the culture and behaviour of people and that is clearly illustrated in the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It boils down to the fact that I am not jealous of anyone in China. The feeling of powerlessness against the ruling party is something I am terrified of and hope to never experience. The Politburo seems to have a much lower threshold than America for throwing a hood over someones head and locking them up forever. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It just seems like the trade off wasn’t worth it. Sure your country is arguably the largest economic superpower in the world but where is your ~culture~? It just seems bland. Relevant quote from the book:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let your public self be like rice in a dinner: bland and inconspicuous, taking on the flavors of its surroundings while giving off no flavor of its own.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here are my favourite highlights from the book, none of which are properly cited:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;She was also moved by the way he cared for his widowed father. On their second date, he proposed marriage to her on the subway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don’t bother looking for favoritism or nepotism here. Work hard, and your success will be clear in your results. Don’t bother kissing ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’d rather cry in a BMW than smile on a bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the more violent the body contact of the sports you watch, the lower the class.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the quantity of money passing through Macau would exceed that of Las Vegas six times over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Chinese were found to take consistently larger risks than Americans of comparable wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Li urged us to soak our feet in hot water before bed—he said it would help with jet lag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Department had a breadth of authority over the realm of ideas in China that Anne-Marie Brady, a scholar who studied it, compared to the “Vatican’s influence over the Catholic world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[The Department] encompassed, by one estimate, a propaganda officer for every one hundred Chinese citizens.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was more important than ever, Party scholars pointed out, to “make their thinking conform with the dominant ideology, thereby standardizing people’s behaviour.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hu Shuli had a singular profile. She was an incurable muckraker, but had cultivated first-name familiarity with some of China’s most powerful Party leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Her interviewees included a promising young cadre in city government whose openness to the free market had earned him the nickname the God of Wealth. His name was Xi Jinping, and years later he would become the president of China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Almost nine out of ten Chinese approved of the way things were going in their country—the highest share of any of the twenty-four countries surveyed that spring by the Pew Research Center. (In the United States, by comparison, just two out of ten voiced such approval.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The United States brags about its political system, but the president says one thing during the election, something else when he takes office, something else at midterm, and something else when he leaves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, the culture of the Web was an almost perfect opposite of the culture of the Communist Party: Chinese leaders cherished solemnity, conformity, and secrecy; the Web sanctified informality, newness, and, above all, disclosure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Authenticity, or the appearance of it, had become the rarest of assets in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When the Party praised “democracy,” it meant “democratic centralism,” the concept of debate within its own ranks, and unquestioning adherence to final decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The instinct to shield the public from unflattering facts was absurdly at odds with the openness and sophistication in other parts of Chinese life, and it seemed to cheapen what ordinary Chinese people had worked so hard to achieve.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The night before his trial, his lawyer was detained; Chen was represented by court-appointed attorneys, who called no witnesses. He was found guilty of destroying property and disrupting traffic and was sentenced to four years and three months in prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the middle of April, human rights groups were calling it the largest crackdown on expression since Tiananmen Square two decades earlier. Two hundred people had been questioned or placed under house arrest; another thirty-five were presumed to be in detention. The list included not only old-line dissidents, but also social media celebrities and journalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the first time in history, the People’s Republic was spending more on domestic security than on foreign defense; it was devoting more money to policing and surveilling its own people than it was on defending against threats from abroad.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How much of the drama was light and how much was dark? How much was about opportunity and how much was about repression?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why the most famous image from China in the past thirty years was not of its economic rise but of the man standing in front of the tank near Tiananmen Square.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A study found that 70 percent of Chinese social media users relied on social media as their main source of news; in America, that number was 9 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The ugly side of China’s growth is perhaps most clearly illustrated by the train crash. Its cause was completely preventable, which only served to propel the incident to an even higher level of fame. The core problem is illustrated below:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“The maintenance people weren’t familiar enough with their jobs, and they didn’t want to stop the train. They didn’t dare.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;^ China’s growth takes president over everything, even citizens own safety.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;China’s most famous public works project was an ecosystem almost perfectly hospitable to corruption—opaque, unsupervised, and overflowing with cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Central government was worried that if he really succeeded in giving out four hundred million in bribes he would essentially have bought a government position. That’s why he was arrested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Public servants—officially earning twenty or thirty thousand dollars a year—became such frequent shoppers at Gucci and Louis Vuitton that high-end boutiques in Beijing ran out of stock whenever the National People’s Congress was in session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In weak democracies, people paid their way into office by buying votes; in a state where there were no votes to buy, you paid the people who doled out the jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Corruption bruuh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By 2012 the richest seventy members of China’s national legislature had a net worth of almost ninety billion dollars—more than ten times the combined net worth of the entire U.S. Congress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Bo Xilai looked like a movie star.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Scandal was becoming the backbeat to China’s rise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Oven if local bureaucrats were corrupt, its top leaders so exemplified wisdom, justice, and meritocracy that dissent and direct elections were superfluous and obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Wealth was hard for the Party to explain, so it decided not to try: within twenty-four hours, the government blocked the Bloomberg website—it would stay blocked in China for the foreseeable future—and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It would cost the company millions in lost sales and advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“He and his family can’t stay in China. It’s no longer safe,” she said. “Something will happen. It will look like an accident. Nobody will know what happened. He’ll just be found dead.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The New York Times relied on corporate records to calculate that in the years that Prime Minister Wen Jiabao was in office, his family amassed assets worth $2.7 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“When the rules favor the rule-makers, they are applied; when they do not, they are ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The inequality index:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(An independent calculation put the figure at 0.61, higher than the level in Zimbabwe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;People had a surprisingly high tolerance for the rise of the plutocracy. What they resented were the obstacles that prevented them from joining it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In all, authorities executed at least fourteen yuan billionaires in the span of eight years, on charges ranging from pyramid schemes to murder for hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In relation to FOXCON and the suicide nets, etc:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Outsiders were quick to imagine a sweatshop, but this explanation was not quite right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All websites are not to repost the news headlined, “UN Releases World Happiness Report, and China Ranks No. 112.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Foshan is a market town, the home of enormous open-air emporiums, one after another: Iron and Steel World and Flower and Plant World and Children’s Clothing Town, which sells enough clothes each year to dress every kid in America, twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instantly, the story of the seventeen passersby began to spread across China, and it provoked a surge of self-recrimination. The writer Zhang Lijia asked, “How can we possibly win respect and play the role of a world leader if this is a nation with 1.4 billion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In the years of the boom, people had picked up &lt;strong&gt;more reasons to fear the law than to trust it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;How could China ever hope to invent the next big thing, the next Facebook, if it didn’t dare to let its people use this one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A terrifying illustration of the governments control. Not quite blatant oppression, but a more quiet insidious suppression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The city diverted bus routes to bypass the courthouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Racism:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In Beijing, some shopkeepers hung signs in their windows like this one, in English, at a restaurant: THIS SHOP DOES NOT RECEIVE THE JAPANESE, THE PHILIPPINES, THE VIETNAMESE AND DOG. In this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Zhai Xiaobing, a man who worked at an investment fund in Beijing, tweeted a geeky joke that compared the meeting to a new apocalypse movie, he was arrested and held for three weeks.
^ Three weeks for  tweet???&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The windows of public buses were taped shut. The city banned pleasure boats from the lakes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;the only Tibetans at the Great Hall were members of the official Tibetan delegation, who brought news that Lhasa, their capital, had been voted “the happiest city in China”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;conducted a “Chinese Dream” survey, asking whether people supported one-party rule and believed in socialism, 80 percent of the three thousand respondents replied “no” to both questions,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[on flights]]></title><description><![CDATA[Boarding a flight is kinda weird. First, the AC105 has an absurd amount of people onboard. 
I wonder if the rising property value of a city…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2017-11-15-on-flights/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2017-11-15-on-flights/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Boarding a flight is kinda weird. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the AC105 has an absurd amount of people onboard.
I wonder if the rising property value of a city can be associated with how many people regularly commute there. The correlation is present for this flight. The line to board was the longest I’ve ever seen and rent in Vancouver makes me want to cry.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While walking from the terminal to the plane in that tunnel thing, I pass by a separate door used only by business class passengers. This is the first in a series of disappointments.
As I enter the plane, I recall Dante’s Divine Comedy; Inferno, Purgatory and Paradise. Though not in that order.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I walk past Paradise first. What I assume to be aggressively rich people are already seated and have to endure the somewhat hostile stares of all the lower class plebs walking past them. It this their punishment for paying such an absurd amount of money for a plane ticket? Wouldn’t they rather board after everyone else so as to avoid the awkward stares? I would.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Premium economy is after, which I suppose is Purgatory. The seats evolve from thrones to generous car seats.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Next is “preferred economy” which only serves to dishearten me more as I realize how low I’ve stooped to get on this plane. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That worry lasts only 5 seconds, or thirty depending on how efficient the people ahead of you are at packing the overhead compartments, until I arrive at the sea of regular economy seats. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I glance over the faces of the plebs. Given their location in the plane, they seem extraordinarily dignified and almost disgusted by their surroundings.  I can’t help but read the thoughts behind their expressions of misery: “Aren’t I special enough to be in the front?”, “Don’t I deserve it?”. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A plane is a unique situation where middle to high-income people are reduced to taking common transport, like a bus. Of course, being on a plane is nothing like being on a bus, but that’s not the point.
I’m trying to say that the type of middle-income people who don’t usually take public transportation are &lt;em&gt;forced&lt;/em&gt; to if they want to travel by air. Everyone is reduced to the same level, rid of income separation for the most part. The size of your seat is the same as your neighbour’s, no matter your background. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless you are in Purgatory or Paradise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The act of sharing space with a stranger is so uncomfortable to me that I would assume most people within their means would pay to be rid of that experience. That seems to be the problem. Our society nowadays seems hell-bent on not caring about anything and remaining distant from everyone (very general statement that I will not justify).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That’s why it seems weird that all these people have agreed to exist in these circumstances for five hours. Those two things don’t make sense together.
I guess I’ve found the exact amount of value people place on their personal comfort.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All that said, the actual economy class seat isn’t all that bad. I’m 5’9” and 150 lbs and can sit somewhat comfortably. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More than your physical dimensions though, I think mastering the politics around seat manipulation are the key to a comfortable flight. Notably, armrest control and seat back position. My answers for both are simple. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In terms of the seat back. You have every right to lean your seat back as much as you like. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In some circumstances a full seat recline would be strange, as is exemplified by the passenger in front of me who is taking a nap at 45 degrees as the flight crew is walking by with lunch, but never unacceptable. The button is there for a reason and it’s stupid not to use it. There is not doubt it causes discomfort for your behind neighbour, as I am experiencing now, but that can always be somewhat alleviated with them reclining their own seat. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Armrests are slightly more difficult. As in most situations, I notice that older people assume the right to them immediately. Ageism. The key here is persistence. Find a purchase on the armrest and stay there. That is assuming the middle of the armrest, the most valuable position, is not taken yet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[on behavioural economics]]></title><description><![CDATA[this post is incompleteProblem: People repeatedly make decisions that undermine their own long term well being.Solution: Give people the…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2017-11-03-on-behavioural-economics/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2017-11-03-on-behavioural-economics/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Problem: People repeatedly make decisions that undermine their own long term well being.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Solution: Give people the satisfaction they need in the short term &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the outcomes that want in the long term.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Human don’t make good decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Health&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Stop smoking&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Exercise more&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Education&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Study better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Teach better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn better&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Personal Finance&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Save more money&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Example: &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The Nudge Unit in the UK government.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Leading People:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=uqXVAo7dVRU&quot;&gt;Danny Kahneman&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Amos Tversky&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Richard Thaler&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Nassim Taleb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[on the timelessness of skateboarding]]></title><description><![CDATA[this post is incompleteA culture tied to an object so completely, they become impossible to separate. Examples:A skateboard and skating…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2017-10-13-on-the-timeless-beauty-of-skateboarding/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2017-10-13-on-the-timeless-beauty-of-skateboarding/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A culture tied to an object so completely, they become impossible to separate. Examples:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A skateboard and skating culture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Soccer ball?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;iPhone and rich white kids&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Breakdancing and hip hop and graffiti&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;this is just here to remind me to write about this&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[on internet dialogues]]></title><description><![CDATA[Don't try to argue with someone on the internet.sorry im gonna finish this someday]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2017-09-03-on-internet-dialogues/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2017-09-03-on-internet-dialogues/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Don&apos;t try to argue with someone on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;sorry im gonna finish this someday&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[on the stock market]]></title><description><![CDATA[this post is incompleteMost investing is gambling.I realized this after reading Nassim Taleb's book, Fooled by Randomness. To summarize…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2017-07-20-on-the-stock-market/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2017-07-20-on-the-stock-market/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
After spending 18 years of my life idolizing rich investment bankers on Wall Street, I have come to a brutal realization:&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most investing is gambling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realized this after reading Nassim Taleb&apos;s book, Fooled by Randomness. To summarize, Taleb proves that behaviours like hindsight bias and pattern-seeking are widely prevalent in today&apos;s society, especially in the investment banking sector. Often, bankers are victim to completely random occurrences in the market, yet attribute them to &quot;skill&quot; and &quot;foresight&quot;. I wrote a bit about this:
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A striking example of this behaviour is the justification for the start of World War 1. As was drilled into me in high school, the assassination of Franz Ferdinand and the escalating tension and militarization in various countries predicted this international conflict. The ensuing World War seems to have been inevitable - after the events have transpired. This is an example of hindsight bias. As Niall Ferguson, a professor of history at Harvard, makes clear in his paper &lt;em&gt;The international bond market between the 1848 revolution and the outbreak of the First World War&lt;/em&gt;, war bond prices were steady. The world had not noticed these so-called significant events. &lt;b&gt;If these hints towards the upcoming conflict were as clear as we now make them out to be, why did the price of war bonds not rise?&lt;/b&gt; Was there a sudden, universal lack of desire to make profit? or were the events we speak of today not obvious at all. Clearly, the latter is more in line with human nature. &lt;strong&gt;We feel the need to justify events after the fact in order to reassure ourselves that we will see it coming next time.&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;- matthew counts as more evidence for this point
![Small example image](http://kahvipatel.com/archive/Media/nobody2.gif &quot;nobody2&quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
- **You can never win against a computer.**&lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  - It take a human about 300-400 milliseconds to blink. Currently, it takes [High Frequency Trading Firms](http://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/091615/world-high-frequency-algorithmic-trading.asp) (basically computers that trade stocks) [85 nanoseconds](https://www.technologyreview.com/s/602135/high-frequency-trading-is-nearing-the-ultimate-speed-limit/) to execute a trade. So if you think that you are gonna be the fastest one to buy a stock when it goes down, you&apos;re not. To put that into perspective, in the time it take you to blink your eye, _one_ HFT computer could execute 3.5 million trades. Basically, computers are just alot faster that you are.
  &lt;br&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unpredictable in the short term, predictable in the long term: The only certain way to make money in the stock market is over time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://awealthofcommonsense.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/SPX-Time-Frames.png&quot; alt=&quot;Small example image&quot; title=&quot;investing chart&quot;&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
^if you invest in an S&amp;P 500 index, you can basically flip a coin to see whether you will make money tommorow. In a decade though, you have a much higher chance of profit.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
This is a excerpt from *Naked Statistics*
&gt; The S&amp;P 500 is a nice example of what an index can and should do. The index is made up of the share prices of the 500 leading U.S. companies, each weighted by its market value (so that bigger companies have more weight in the index than smaller companies). The index is a simple and accurate gauge of what is happening to the share prices of the largest American companies at any given time. 
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
  okay, here&apos;s a research paper
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Kahvi Patel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Research Paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Tutorial 9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;April 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2017&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Tutor: S. Boos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;br&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;In the early 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century, the separation between scientific and non-scientific theories was vague. The most practical way to distinguish a theory as scientific was to determine whether it was known a posteriori; relied on an empirical method. This meant that astrology, given its vast amounts of observed information, qualified as a scientific theory. In 1919, Karl Popper sought to contrive an alternative separation. Falsifiability was the philosophical term he coined. With this theory, Popper set the groundwork for the modern scientific method and, simultaneously, addressed the problem of induction that had troubled Hume and many other philosophers before him. Popper’s theory of Falsification, however, not only has its roots in philosophy, but in human nature. As has been the case throughout history, human nature is more prone towards what Popper distinguished as “pseudo-scientific” theories rather than “scientific” ones. Our inherent desires are what make Popper’s theory of Falsification especially relevant; Demarcation is a tool to fight against our own misleading natural instincts. In order to repress this widespread malpractice, we must employ tactics of doubt exemplified by philosophers like Descartes and Socrates in order to enforce a more logical, and therefore more productive, general consciousness. As Popper originally described in his theory, falsification, rather than confirmation, must be what we seek in order to prove our own theories.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;For Popper, the reason for distinguishing between theories was not for lack of truth; “it was not my doubting the truth of those other…theories which bothered me, but something else” (Popper 32). Neither was it because of the different nature of some theories or the variability in accuracy they provided. In fact, what bothered Popper were the incessant “confirming instances” relating to the “pseudo-scientific theories” in question. Freud’s theory of psychoanalysis, for example, was supported repeatedly by whatever the psychologist theorized. In other words, every event confirmed the theory. This practice has a flaw.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;I may illustrate this by two very different examples of human behavior: that of a man who pushes a child into the water with the intention of drowning it; and that of a man who sacrifices his life in an attempt to save the child. Each of these two cases can be explained with equal ease in Freudian and in Adlerian terms. According to Freud the first man suffered from repression (say, of some component of his Oedipus complex), while the second man had achieved sublimation. According to Adler the first man suffered fro feelings of inferiority (producing perhaps the need to prove to himself that he dared to commit some crime), and so did the second man (whose need was to prove to himself that he dared to rescue the child). (Popper 35)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;This situation demonstrates the ambiguity of Freud’s (and Adler’s) theory. The result, no matter how unexpected or crazy, can always be justified. This method was in direct contrast to another Popper had witnessed; Einstein’s theory of gravitation. Whereas Freud’s theory relied on explanation, Einstein’s relied on prediction. More specifically, one sought confirmation, the other sought falsification. Alarmingly though, both relied on empirical evidence and the method of induction, thus classifying them both, for now, as scientific theories. Importantly, Popper did not attempt to discredit the validity of Freud’s theory, although he may have done so unconsciously. His intention was merely to distinguish it. The significance of this separation cannot be understated. As history progressed, a scientific method was developed around Popper’s falsifiability and a distinguishable separation began to emerge between science and others things.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;More than just a method for distinction between theories, Falsification has significance in human behavior. In general, humans are programmed to ignore events that do not agree with their beliefs and pay attentions to ones that do. This behavior is called confirmation bias. Unfortunately, it has been proven to exist throughout many studies, the most famous of which is the Wason Selection Task.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;He presented subjects with the three-number sequence 2, 4, 6, and asked them to try to guess the rule generating it. Their method of guessing was to produce other three-number sequences, to which the experimenter would respond “yes” or “no” depending on whether the new sequences were consistent with the rule. Once confident with their answers, the subjects would formulate the rule. The correct rule was “numbers in ascending order,” nothing more. Very few subjects discovered it because in order to do so they had to offer a series in descending order (that the experimenter would say “no” to). (Taleb 123)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;This experiment demonstrates our inherent instinct to always seek confirmation for our own hypothesis, or theories, instead or trying to discredit them. Once the subjects had formulated a rule, their only intention became trying to find a pattern that fit it instead of trying to supply a series that was inconsistent with their hypothesis. Our natural human behavior compels us to seek confirmation. The parallels here are widespread. Today, most people gather their information (and biases) from the news. And there is more news today than ever before. The constant news cycle compounds biases. People have access to countless sources of evidence, or &quot;number series&quot;, which they use to confirm their own opinions. It becomes much more difficult to attempt to disprove your own opinion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;A most poignant example of this behavior of confirmation bias is the political polarization that currently exists in the United States: both sides seek confirmation for their own theories, never falsification. Popper’s Demarcation seems to work against human instinct. For instance, Freud’s theory of psychoanalysis is more easily understandable than Einstein’s theory of gravity and thus more attractive. This inherent preference leads to many human patterns of behavior, such as illusion of control and hindsight bias. When a need to explain something arises, we are predisposed to justify our theory by seeking confirmation instead of testing it. &lt;b&gt;A striking example of this behavior is the justification for the start of World War 1. Clearly, the assassination of Franz Ferdinand and the escalating tension and militarization in various countries might predict international conflict. The ensuing World War seems to have been inevitable - after the events have transpired. This is an example of hindsight bias which generates pseudo-scientific theories. As Niall Ferguson, a professor of history at Harvard, makes clear in his paper &lt;em&gt;The international bond market between the 1848 revolution and the outbreak of the First World War&lt;/em&gt;, the world had not noticed these so-called significant events, as evidenced by the flat lining of war bond prices. If these hints towards the upcoming conflict were as clear as we now make them out to be, why did the price of war bonds not rise? Was there a sudden, universal lack of desire to make profit? or were the events we speak of today not obvious at all. Clearly, the latter is more in line with human nature. The pseudo-scientific theory suggests that the war started because of an episode of tension and militarization. This is an example of seeking confirmation and hindsight bias. We feel the need to justify events after the fact in order to reassure ourselves that we will see it coming next time.&lt;/b&gt; More often than not, however, our theories for the cause of past events are vulnerable to falsification. Until those theories in question can withstand falsification, this practice of explanation is useless.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Our constant desire to fabricate an illusion of control leads us to justify theories in unreliable ways. When theories are not tested with falsification, they can lead us to misleading conclusions or a false sense of security. In 470 BC, Socrates exposed society’s wrongful act of gathering, spreading and reciting knowledge that had illogical grounds. In what we now call “Socratic Dialogue”, Socrates reduced his subject’s opinions to a single thesis which was often illogical. Through this, he proved the Delphi’s prophecy true: he was, in fact, “the wisest of men”. This title, however, did not originate from vast education or far-reaching experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;I am wiser than this man; it is likely that neither of us knows anything worthwhile, but he thinks he knows something when he does not, whereas when I do not know, neither do I think I know; so I am likely to be wiser than he to this small extent, that I do not think I know what I do not know. (Plato 3)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Socrates was merely the only man who knew the extent of his own ignorance. Today, we encounter a similar situation. Many of our generally accepted theories and personal opinions are illogical and/or justified by a flawed method. More importantly though, the vast majority of society &lt;em&gt;does not realize&lt;/em&gt; this. Descartes provides another apt exemplar. His doubt, though undoubtedly extreme, was important to build a foundation of truth upon which the rest of his beliefs were founded.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot; name=&quot;GoBack&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;It is as though they [my beliefs] had a right to a place in my belief-system as a result of long occupation and the law of custom. These habitual opinions of mine are indeed highly probable; although they are in a sense doubtful, as I have shown, it is more reasonable to believe than to deny them. But if I go on viewing them in that light I shall never get out of the habit of confidently assenting to them. To conquer that habit, therefore, I had better switch right around and pretend (for a while) that these former opinions of mine are utterly false and imaginary. I shall do this until I have something to counter-balance the weight of old opinion, and the distorting influence of habit no longer prevents me from judging correctly. (Descartes 2)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;The important parallel here is doubt. To doubt one’s own belief is the most basic and true form of falsification. We must draw from influences of the past to create a better future. We must take advice from Socrates and Descartes and question our own theories and opinions in order to arrive at the roots of our beliefs. We must acknowledge our own ignorance in order to take the next step towards progress.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Popper’s philosophy was originally meant to distinguish scientific theories. His philosophy of Demarcation, however, went beyond science, and addressed two methods of thinking. Unfortunately for humanity, we are prone to the less reliable mode of thinking: one that seeks confirmation. This behavior has led to a worrying trend in human history. By analyzing the past and present, we may understand how hindsight bias and the illusion of control reveal themselves in society and how they are the result of instinctual human behavior. With the problem assessed and recognized, we may understand it and endeavor to solve it. Turning to philosophers of the past, such as Descartes and Socrates, helps us recognize the underlying theme of doubt in their work and leads us to an apt solution. Doubt is perhaps the truest form of falsification and should be practiced by individuals today in order to help justify beliefs. The practice of seeking to falsify one’s own beliefs takes courage and determination but is ultimately the path towards a more reliable future. Unless we begin challenging our beliefs, instead of seeking confirmation of them, moral progress will slow. If we begin using Popper’s method in our lives, diversity of opinion and success will be the result.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Works Cited&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Popper, Karl. &lt;em&gt;Conjectures and Refutations&lt;/em&gt;. Basic Books, 1962.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Nicholas Taleb, Nassim. &lt;em&gt;The Black Swan: The Impact of the Highly Improbable.&lt;/em&gt; Random House, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Ferguson, Niall. “Political risk and the international bond market between the 1848 revolution and the outbreak of the First World War.” &lt;em&gt;Economic History Review&lt;/em&gt;, Vol 29, no. 1, February 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Plato. &lt;em&gt;Apology&lt;/em&gt;. translated by G.M.A. Grube, Hackett Publishing Company, 2000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Descartes, Renee. &lt;em&gt;Meditations on First Philosophy&lt;/em&gt;. translated by Jonathan F. Bennett, Cambridge University Press, 1996.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br&gt;
inspired by Nassim Nicholas Taleb and [Fooled by Randomness](http://jamesclear.com/book-summaries/fooled-by-randomness) (great read)</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[the hair question]]></title><description><![CDATA[Current State: Long hairPros:Looks better than short hair IMOTakes less time to prepare (Effort to Look ratio is great)Less money spent on…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2017-05-10-the-hair-question/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2017-05-10-the-hair-question/</guid><pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;Current State: Long hair&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looks better than short hair IMO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Takes less time to prepare (Effort to Look ratio is great)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less money spent on haircuts (more efficient for financials)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looks slightly better with hats&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compliments facial hair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When let down, it is impossible to manage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Gets greasy quite quickly (Discourages working out)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Is sometimes uncomfortable when in bad bun&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Takes a long time to dry (Discourages working out)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extra weight?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cumbersome with hoods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discourages lying down&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looks less professional/trustworthy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Alternative: Short hair&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easier to manage&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Would be more comfortable and usable&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less weight?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Less time to dry (encourages working out)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Looks more professional/trustworthy&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could add height&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doesn’t look as good IMO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Requires more haircuts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;More time to prepare in the morning&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Doesn’t really compliment the facial hair&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;oct 2017 update: I have short hair now.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[drafts]]></title><description><![CDATA[take two deep breaths before reading or else youll probably faint tinder biosI’ll fuck you harder than trump is fucking middle americaWhen I…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2017-02-03-drafts/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2017-02-03-drafts/</guid><pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;take two deep breaths before reading or else youll probably faint &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tinder bios&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’ll fuck you harder than trump is fucking middle america&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;When I&apos;m high I turn into Jaden Smiths twitter account&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I’ll pay more attention to you than dj khaled does to his garden&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The day Trump got elected I laughed so hard my left lung came out.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I lift often. Lift people out of poverty that is. I volunteer bi weekly at an local community center.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If you&apos;re ever beside me on a plane, i&apos;ll give you the armrest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;tweets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Appointing Rick perry to head the EPA is like appointing ryan lochte to teach calculus&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are the blinkers on cars always off tempo like fuck just sync up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yes sir it is completely fine that you are reclining your seat this early into the flight please carry on&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;gets cramp walking away from the cafeteria&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wish i could talk with one percent of the confidence that migos have when they rap gibberish&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sometimes you have great professors and sometimes you have a textbook that managed to learn how to speak&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Trusting Putin is like trusting that Jimmy Fallons laugh is actually real&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if it takes me three weeks to learn how to recline the chairs in Killam then yeah I&apos;m probably gonna fail this exam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am so habitually apathetic that a plane could literally emit a barking noise during takeoff and I wouldnt look up from my phone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My only optimism after the election is waiting for the moment that trump doesnt remember what the acronym for a gov agency stands for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;its not that I don’t wanna workout, its that I don’t wanna work&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why are the blinkers on cars always off tempo like fuck just sync up&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why doesn’t Conan grow his beard back&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Im pretty sure that becoming more mature just means you get less excited at things&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The US needs to expand its nuclear arsenal like Nickelback needs to release a new album&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I wish when I registered for course at uni there were reviews like on Amazon&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even though I don’t want it to happen i feel like dude perfect could perform at the next Super Bowl halftime show and I wouldn’t be surprised&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;is like saying that Facebook is good for objective journalism &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;why can’t I hibernate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why am I paying 10 grad in tuition when a 5 minute youtube video teaches me more than a 50 minute lecture&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hey @spotify when I search for a song and play it does’t mean I want to keep listening to same versions of that same song afterwards&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;who invented single ply toilet paper&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fuck y’all I’m buying my siblings instagram followers for christmas&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[on my career pt.2]]></title><description><![CDATA[Disclaimer: This was transcribed and lightly edited from a voice recording.So I’m thinking about my career choice, what I want to do in life…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2017-01-08-on-my-career-pt.2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2017-01-08-on-my-career-pt.2/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 08 Jan 2017 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;h3&gt;Disclaimer: This was transcribed and lightly edited from a voice recording.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I’m thinking about my career choice, what I want to do in life, how my trajectory came to be and I think I’ve noticed a pattern.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I was really into graphic design. I really latched onto that as a career path. I remember quite vividly telling my parents that it was my passion and what I wanted to do for the rest of my life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That passion resulted in some pretty substantial things. I ended up running a business based mostly off of my graphic design. The purpose behind that business was never profit, it was just about gaining experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So anyway, I’ve sort of noticed a pattern about my attitude towards a career.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First though, this dialogue is not meant to say that graphic design is what I really should be doing because I don’t think I’ll ever know what I really should be doing; this is not meant as an argument in favour of graphic design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I started out with graphic design. I was very passionate about that. But eventually, I said to myself that it wasn’t good enough. So I went to architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s another way to look at this too. Graphic design is wholly creative, there isn’t math or physics or any kind of science involved generally. Then architecture is a pretty practical blend of creativity and the sciences.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Anyway, I chose to pursue architecture and that was at about the time when I was applying to universities.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The reason I just jumped from graphic design to architecture, if I’m honest with myself, is that architecture looked cooler and looked harder. I am quite certain that it had nothing to do with my passion to design buildings because, although I find it interesting , I do not have that passion. That said, I do have a passion to solve problems, whether it be with math or science or architecture. To sum up though, I know that the main reason why I jumped from graphic design to architecture is because it was more challenging. So I started focusing on that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The grass is always greener on the other side. I began to idolize and really focus on achieving a successful career in architecture.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I applied to a good architecture program and got in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s at that point that I came crashing back down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are many reasons why I didn’t feel as motivated about architecture after I got the offer versus before. At first, my drive was mainly to overcome an obstacle. I really wanted to achieve admission to that program.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, once I received the offer, the other side became too clear and defined. It scared me to think about a career path in architecture. That said though, from an outside perspective, it seemed obvious that architecture was my desired career path. In my head, however, f I realized that I wasn’t sure about architecture and that the reasons for my attraction towards it were unfounded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I decided to take year at King’s college in Halifax, where I am now, and my plan was to do architecture after.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But over the winter break the pattern remerged. I wanted to do something more difficult. I wanted to make it harder for myself and so I panicked. I became really uncomfortable with the idea of going to Waterloo next year and there were a couple of reasons for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First, the fact that I am not passionate about architecture. Also important is the isolated campus and vast dissimilarity to Halifax. I wouldn’t have access to a campus or electives. I would see the same people everyday. That freaked me out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I gravitated towards engineering. I became quite obsessed, and still am, about getting into a good engineering program. To justify the switch to myself, I made up a lot of reasons that I’m still not sure are true or not. Reasons like: I need a masters in architecture to get certified as an architect; the job market didn’t look great; the program in Waterloo was very specialized, etc.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To elaborate on my worries about the program: It felt as though once I got into that program there wasn’t anywhere to branch off to. The program lead to one place and that was a career architecture. Had I been passionate and really interested in architecture maybe I would’ve liked that idea. I know now that career paths are unpredictable and often never end up where you expect them to, but that imagined certainty was a really intimidating thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But with all that said, then, and even now, I have this weird mindset where whatever your undergraduate degree is, that is what you will be doing for the rest of your life. Of course that isn’t true, but the Waterloo architecture program made it seem like that.
Anyway, I got cold feet about the program and decided that I would to go into engineering. My logic behind that choice is I would be exposed to a lot of more subjects like computer science, physics, mechanics, etc. Just a bunch of things that I think are important to know.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This all relates to the pattern I was talking about before.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I started with graphic design and wanted something harder so I went to architecture and wanted something harder so I went to engineering.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If I have these skills; if I had the ability to do these things, and why shouldn’t I capitalize on them and get the degree that will make me successful and well-payed and stuff.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I’m certain that had I not been good at math or physics, I would have passionately pursued graphic design. I think I would’ve truly enjoyed that career path.
But with the knowledge that I can do all these things, it makes the pursuit of graphic design all the more pointless seeming.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And thats where I’m at right now. I think this chat has kind of cleared up some things for me. It’s a really weird thing to think about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[on my career]]></title><description><![CDATA[The line between hobby, occupation and passion is becoming uncomfortably important for me. Yet the more I think on it, the less it gets…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2016-12-20-on-my-career/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2016-12-20-on-my-career/</guid><pubDate>Tue, 20 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The line between hobby, occupation and passion is becoming uncomfortably important for me. Yet the more I think on it, the less it gets defined. I think of myself as a pragmatic person. So when someone asks “What would you do if money were no object?” it seems like a forgone idea. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I think back, one turning point in my outlook on the future came in my high school focus program. Reality set in when we were asked to sort ourselves into our desired professions. I ended up with the nerdy, timid graphic designers while the smarter, louder group of desiring architects sat across the room. In that moment, the reality of the career choice I was making set in. I had considered the struggle of being a graphic designer and the twisted path it would bring to my life, but this pushed me over the edge.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I realize this seems dramatic. And the associations I am making with an entire profession based on this are ridiculous. But, even reflecting back on this moment, I don’t think I could’ve changed my mind.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So I grasped on the whatever was closest. That turned out to be architecture. Why did I do this? Personally, I explain it to myself as a &quot;need to be challenged&quot;. Although my logic surrounding that is definitely sketchy. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;More seriously though, my concern is that my “fire” will burn out. That I’ll become lazy or unmotivated. That everything will become less important and blasé to me. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When that moment comes, where will I be? Working a well paying engineering job? or struggling as a graphic designer where the only thing keeping food in the table is my passion. In my view that risk is large, compounded by the fact that I have a very comfortable safety net of two wealthy doctors that wouldn’t let me starve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It all comes down to perspective. Whether I consciously realize it or not, I am constantly comparing myself to my KCVI peers. The ones that I know. And every single one is either in medicine, commerce or engineering. I compare myself to them and realize that theirs is a more pragmatic, safe approach to a career. I read about unemployment and undergrads waiting table. I read about people not having enough money to retire. I read about graphic designers doing multiple hours of work for next to nothing. Is following my “passion” really worth that risk? So far, I would say no.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[scrambled eggs]]></title><description><![CDATA[here's how to make scrambled eggs with no objective instructions!]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2016-12-18-scrambled-eggs/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2016-12-18-scrambled-eggs/</guid><pubDate>Sun, 18 Dec 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;here&apos;s how to make scrambled eggs with no objective instructions!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/8iYcGz_nrj8&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[Avery Gates]]></title><description><![CDATA[The basil was wilted. Soft and slouching. Something dying among the living. I shuddered, picking it out from the other fresh plants and…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2016-04-25-Avery-Gates/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2016-04-25-Avery-Gates/</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2016 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;The basil was wilted. Soft and slouching. Something dying among the living. I shuddered, picking it out from the other fresh plants and throwing it into the cart. I had gone to the doctor on Tuesday, it was now Monday of the following week. I still hadn’t digested the news. The fluorescent lights of the store made my eyes ache. I walked further down the aisle, spotting some moldy cauliflower along the way.
“Why do you guys sell produce anyway?”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I turned to answer and immediately regretted it. Brandon was my trainee for the day. I didn’t like Brandon. He was almost as tall as me and apparently didn’t know how to operate a shower. I could almost see my reflection in the shiny black mess on his head.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“We didn’t until recently. I guess corporate decided that people want to buy everything in one place.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“You can do that at Loblaws though,”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I turned and started walking, letting his question hang unanswered, “Yes. Yes you can.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I hadn’t mentioned my diagnosis to anyone. I figured I’d get too much unwanted attention. I was going to call my parents when I got back, but never did. Pity was something I intentionally avoided, no matter the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I saw Brandon glance at the clock. It was 4:45. The store was completely empty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We walked out at 5:30. Closing up took longer that usual with Brandon delaying each step.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was winter and the moon was already in the sky. I could see my breath. There was no wind and it hung motionless in the air. Brandon started walking towards the bus stop.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There was a crack from across the parking lot. I glanced to where it had come from. Another crack. There was something shiny in front of Loblaws. Another crack. Three men. They were trying to pry open the doors. Brandon had stopped walking and was looking for the noise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the men spotted us. He started walking in our direction.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;I stood still. I was tired. I was annoyed. I was also angry.
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“WHAT DO YOU THINK YOU’RE DOING”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The man froze.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“GET OUT” I screamed, my throat already raw.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It felt good.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“GO. LEAVE.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Brandon had frozen mid-step. He was staring at me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Like a deer in the headlights,” I thought. I still didn’t like Brandon.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The man had started walking back towards his friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I considered following him. But then I considered my age. And my health insurance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The men had left.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Suddenly I felt tired. My chest was heaving and my hands were shaking.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It was only Monday.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The End.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[NPBHS]]></title><description><![CDATA[(i don't really like this one)To shave or to leave school, that was the question. Comply and go against my values, or stand for what I…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//2015-03-05-NBPHS/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//2015-03-05-NBPHS/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;(i don&apos;t really like this one)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To shave or to leave school, that was the question. Comply and go against my values, or stand for what I believe - freedom of appearance and expression - and risk rejection and isolation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trip was the furthest I had ever been from home. I was to attend New Plymouth Boys High School for the duration of our six-month stay in New Zealand. I had assumed that the schools there were similar to the ones in Canada. On my first day, I discovered I was wrong. I had just come through the front doors when the assistant principal (ironically named Mr. Hope) pulled me aside to discuss my neatly trimmed goatee: “I’m not sure what goes on where you come from, but you’re going to have to be clean shaven in order to attend this school”. At first I thought it was a joke. Of course I had known about their dress policy beforehand but everyone had assured me that they wouldn’t obsess about it on the first day of school. “Do you think I could keep it for today, and come back tomorrow clean shaven?” “No, no you cannot be present in the school without adhering to the dress code.” I stared dumbfounded at Mr. Hope (who was himself sporting a thick brown beard). I had to make a decision.
The requirement to change my appearance for no substantial reason seemed absurd. In my own high school, a student’s appearance was only questioned when it prevented other students from learning. I was having trouble determining how my goatee would interfere with education. But there was no time to think. I was handed a razor and shown to a bathroom. I emerged clean-shaven for the first time in two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The weeks that followed were difficult. After the demeaning experience of the first day, I had little motivation to attend school at all. I thought of NPBHS as a sinister institution that preyed on individuality. I was critical of the school’s teachers, the classrooms, and the curriculum. Yet even as I criticized the school, I began to meet students like Connor Apimerika. Connor is an amazing artist. We spent hours sitting beside each other in art class, and he helped motivate me to improve my own skills. He and other students helped me realize that I should not judge a whole culture through a single experience. Although it was humiliating to temporarily suspend my values, that decision had a reward.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Being in a foreign country for six months taught me many things, and most were learned in that high school. I learned that the struggle to fit in to a different environment could sometimes result in antagonistic feelings towards that environment. I imagine that Quest University will be a welcoming environment for most, but to some it may be scary and different – perhaps a bit like NPBHS was to me. Because of my own struggles in a new culture, I can offer empathy and support for people in different learning environments or difficult situations.&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[My Book List]]></title><description><![CDATA[First: Reading a book requires so much of my attention that I never finish books that do not interest me. Therefore, I would recommend all…]]></description><link>https://kahvipatel.com//book-list/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">https://kahvipatel.com//book-list/</guid><pubDate>Thu, 05 Mar 2015 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;First&lt;/em&gt;: Reading a book requires so much of my attention that I never finish books that do not interest me. Therefore, I would recommend all the books listed below. &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This list will be updated continuously.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;u&gt; this year &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Asymmetry&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;em&gt;05/02/19&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The structure of this book is a bit of a puzzle. The first, second and third all act tie together in a subtle way. I like the book because of the content, not the puzzle. Intricate and enjoyed.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Still Me&lt;/b&gt; - &lt;em&gt;23/01/19&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I didn&apos;t realize this book was part of a trilogy until I finished it which I guess is a good thing. It’s a story that focuses around life and growing up and relationships and New York City. I really enjoyed it. A great ending too.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Priestdaddy&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I read this one last year but never wrote about it. This book is hilarious. Focuses on the struggles of masculinity, church, religion, family. Manages to find humour in every one of those topics. I really liked it.
&lt;a href=&quot;/_pages/highlights/Priestdaddy&quot;&gt;Highlights here&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Shoe Dog&lt;/b&gt;- &lt;em&gt;07/01/19&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book motivates yet discourages entrepreneurship for me. The thrill of working towards a vision you create, changing customers’ lives, the idea of having a legacy, are all overwhelmingly desireable. And since Phil seems like the most humble of founding billionaires, the ups and downs of his story are described pretty objectively. But his storytelling leads to many reflections on what he is sacrificing to achieve those goals. And I empathized with those parts more. Knight’s journey makes for a thrilling story either way.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;u&gt; 2018 &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Leviathan Wakes&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I haven’t read any new science-fiction in a while. This book grabbed me. It’s gritty, intricate, emotional and never dull. Will probably keep reading this series. Not sure why I haven’t been reading more science-fiction.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bad Blood&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Read this one quickly. This is the story behind the rise and fall of Theranos. If that company is unknown to you, I highly recommend looking them up. The story is larger than life and illustrates the strange motivations that govern Silicon Valley. It’s disturbing how much they got away with and for how long. It made me question the whole ecosystem. They’ll probably make a movie about it soon.&lt;br&gt;
“…in her [Elizabeth Holmes’s]  all-consuming quest to be the second coming of Steve Jobs amid the gold rush of the “unicorn” boom, there came a point when she stopped listening to sound advice and began to cut corners. Her ambition was voracious and it brooked no interference.”
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Circe&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I love the Greek Gods. Their combination of vanity and absolute power always makes for exciting stories. This book went by quickly. It’s a retelling of &lt;em&gt;The Odyssey&lt;/em&gt; and several other classic Greek tales from the perspective of the Goddess Circe. Reading it felt somewhat similar to Percy Jackson but I wouldn’t recommend it to children. It explores the idea of immortality, love, children, beauty. There is a happy ending.&lt;br&gt;
“he had never met a god [Circe] who enjoyed their divinity less.”
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Naked Economics&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I haven&apos;t finished this book yet. Mostly because it has a tendency to put me to sleep which is convenient since I read it right before bed. Despite that, I enjoy every second I&apos;m awake! Hopefully it will be done by Christmas. (Update: Just finished it)&lt;br&gt;
&lt;a href=&quot;/_pages/highlights/Naked-Economics&quot;&gt;Highlights here&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Orchid and the Wasp&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book reminds me of The Goldfinch. Despite the unusual situations Gael (the protagonist) finds herself in, I &lt;em&gt;believe&lt;/em&gt; in the logic of why she got there. In fact, I feel like that&apos;s where I would be in her shoes despite her facetious, ruthless, manipulative personality. Yet at her core, Gael is motivated by her caring for her family. I guess the ends justify the means.
&lt;a href=&quot;/_pages/highlights/Orchid-and-the-Wasp&quot;&gt;Highlights here&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Looming Tower&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This is the first non-fiction book that has kept me engaged for over a month of regular reading. The book explores Islam, US Policy, personal motivations; and culminates in 9/11. Despite this inevitable conclusion, what kept me reading is the background leading up to the event and not the event itself. My knowledge surrounding the events leading up to 9/11 involving Bin Laden, Sudan, Yemen and Saudi Arabia was murky and misinformed until I started reading this book.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The English Patient&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Not sure how I got through this book. It has exciting moments, but they are few and far between. This book takes a certain type of focus and patience that I barely have. It’s rewarding by the end though. About a group of people who live in an Italian villa after the War. Explores each of their histories, some more than others.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Brief and Wondrous Life of Oscar Wao&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Fun book to read. It goes by fast mostly due to the narrator’s hilarious tone. Follows a family through three generations as they navigate the Dominican Republic and then the United States, but mostly about Oscar Wao. Left me with a melancholy feeling. Important tip: Do not read the introduction, it takes way too long and is discouraging.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Idiot&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book is dense. It took me a while to finish. I haven&apos;t encountered this type of writing style before. It&apos;s abrupt and unique. I identify with the main character and her setting deeply. &lt;a href=&quot;/_pages/highlights/The-Idiot&quot;&gt;Highlights here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;La Belle Sauvage&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I had a vague memory of liking the &lt;em&gt;Golden Compass&lt;/em&gt; trilogy by the same author (Philip Pullman), which is why I read this book. It took me by surprise. The shift of environment and tone after the first half was sudden, but grew on me. One of my favourite main characters in any book. This story carries with it some deeper moral lessons. Set in a similar world as Harry Potter, but more serious and &lt;em&gt;slightly&lt;/em&gt; less supernatural.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2018/05/on-statistics.html&quot;&gt;Naked Statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Until reading this book, I never had a grasp on statistics. I’ve now realized how important it is. The nature of statistics is counter-intuitive and learning the a few important concepts means defeating misinformation in your daily life. It’s dense though.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Obelisk Gate&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The second book in the Broken Earth series. Just as engaging as the first. Sped through this book in two days.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Fifth Season&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I devoured this book. The first in the Broken Earth series. Starts out rough, but keeps you trapped till the end. The first time in a while I’ve actually been enthralled with fantasy.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Death’s End&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A fitting end to an amazing trilogy. This book dives even deeper into fantasy and I believe it completely every step of the way. Contains the most realistic view of our (humanity’s) future, I think.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Dark Forest&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
The book is better than the first (The Three-Body Problem) in the trilogy. Takes a while to get started, but it’s an amazing ride once it does. If you are at all interested in alien life or astrophysics please read this book.&lt;br&gt;
The idea of a “dark forest” is so overarching and terrifying that it my changed my perception of space.&lt;br&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Three-Body Problem&lt;/b&gt; (re-read)&lt;br&gt;
My second favorite science-fiction novel. Involves the Chinese Cultural Revolution, chaotic motion, aliens and a funny cop. Mostly, it keeps engaging you with an overarching mystery. The novel gives you a jarring view of what contact with extra-terrestrial intelligence would feel like.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Annihilation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Unnerving and disturbing. This book is a fictional story that reads like a non-fiction account of reality. Like a black mirror episode in a novel. It’s a quick read too.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Red Sparrow&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A thriller that delves into Russian culture but mostly keeps you reading it at all costs. A combination of James Patterson and John Le Carré. More Patterson than Le Carré though. Also, recipes are provided at the end of every chapter.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;A Brave New World&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A terrifying view on our dystopian future. Even more striking when considered with technologies like CRISPR and stem cells. Asks many questions about human nature.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Pachinko&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A book that navigates through three generations of Korean immigrants in Japan during the Second World War. The story struck a chord with me since I come from a family of immigrants. Vividly illustrates the sacrifices that the older generation makes. Really liked this one.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;A Gentleman in Moscow&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Set in the Soviet Union in Moscow in a famous hotel. A former Count lives from middle to old-age and must raise a adopted child within the walls of the hotel. He makes the best of his experience and we see him deal with the existing and developing culture of Russia. A happy ending.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/12/Age-of-Ambition.html&quot;&gt;Age of Ambition: Chasing Fortune, Truth, and Faith in the New China&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A useful and striking introduction to modern day China. Illustrates the speed at which China is growing and the costs of that growth. It is long.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;u&gt; 2017 &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Fooled by Randomness&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book was the catalyst for my obsession with Behavioural Economics. Nassim Nicholas Taleb effectively eliminated my trust in the global stock market and everyone who works for it. I do not, however, align with his political beliefs. Taleb lays out how we all operate under frightening amounts of randomness. Highly recommend.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Thanks, Obama&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Being deeply immersed in US political news has made working in the White House have a magical allure. This book grounded some of my dreams in reality, but also elevated many more. Being surrounded by capable, hopeful idealists who shape the future of the world everyday will never get old.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Rosie Project&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
I started this book because Bill Gates recommended it. The whole book doesn’t seem grounded in reality, but that doesn’t make it less interesting. It speaks to how people meet each other and what influences us to start or end relationships.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Three-Body Problem&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
See above.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;A Visit from the Goon Squad&lt;/b&gt; (twice its very good)&lt;br&gt;
I love this book. Describes the intertwining lives of Bennie and Sasha. The story feels melancholy the whole way through, but there are enough happy moments to pull you through.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;A Horse Walks Into a Bar&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A dark comedy? Takes place during one evening at a comedy club. I feel like I learned something about performance by reading this book. Also hilarious at times.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Undoing Project&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
A &lt;em&gt;dense&lt;/em&gt; book. About the inception of Behavioural Economics. Follows the relationship of two academics.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;American Kingpin&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
About the founder of the dark web. Draws some pretty blurry moral lines about why the main character is guilty. Recommended by Casey Neistat.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Seveneves&lt;/b&gt; (almost)&lt;br&gt;
Bill Gates said he loved this book so I decided to read it. I was about three-quarters of the way through before the whole plot started getting predicable and too disheartening to follow. Interesting concept though.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;So You’ve Been Publicly Shamed&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book is SOOO relevant today. Describes what it feels like to be on the other side of internet outrage. How a mob mentality can lead to terrible consequences.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Swordspoint&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
As I’ve gotten older, my focus has turned away from fantasy and towards science-fiction. This book is an exception.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Sisters Brothers&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Really good book. A Western with real cowboys and guns. Has a good moral at the end.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Psychopath Test&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Another Jon Ronson book (SYBPS). I’ve always been fascinated by psychopaths and this book centres around what defines them as such. Do they run the world’s largest corporations? Does their existence always result in a lot of dead people?
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;&lt;u&gt; probably before 2017 &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Goldfinch&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This might be my &lt;em&gt;favourite book&lt;/em&gt;. I fell in love with every single character. About a boy and his journey through life.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Buried Giant&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
This book stayed with me. One of the most mature fantasy novels I’ve read. The authors tone is never crowded or too detailed, yet the characters are so easy to empathize with.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Revenant&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Brutal, cunning and savage. Leo Dicaprio and bears. If you liked the movie, you’ll love the book because it’s three times as long.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Secret History&lt;/b&gt;&lt;br&gt;
By the same author who wrote &lt;em&gt;the Goldfinch&lt;/em&gt; (my favourite book). “The story is an inverted detective story, not a whodunit but a &lt;em&gt;whydunit&lt;/em&gt;”. &amp;#x3C;— from Wikipedia
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I will finish these summaries&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;All The Light We Cannot See&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Big Short&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Flash Boys&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Boomerang&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Luminaries&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Martian&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Gone Girl&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Consider the Lobster&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;In the Skin of a Lion&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bad Monkey&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;The Cat’s Table&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;Steve Jobs&lt;/b&gt;  &lt;br&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>