<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kahvi's blog</title>
    <description>I create here sometimes. And rarely captalize.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 19:05:00 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Dec 2017 19:05:00 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>A book review?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;Age of Ambition: Chasing Fortune, Truth, and Faith in the New China&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt; by Evan Osnos &lt;br /&gt;^ is a book I’ve recently read.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most books I read don’t stay with me for long. This one is no different.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This time though, I read on a Kindle and highlighted things so that I might remember the entire book in more detail. This post is my attempt at summarizing the book using those highlighted quotations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China has always been a mystery to me. The variety of culture found in the United States is so broad that I find trouble believing the one-dimensional image I have in my head of China. A country with arguably the most important economy yet I have not idea how it’s run, it’s history, the source of its growth, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, the idea that they’re a communist country? Doesn’t the West hate Commies? Why are we okay with this?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book was easy to read for a couple reasons. First, it is an interesting introduction to a country I know nothing about. It follows personal journeys of people instead of talking about numbers and economics and boring.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Second, it is somewhat reassuring. Here’s a fact that has consistently stuck in my mind: There are more MBA’s graduating every year in China than there are undergrads graduating in the US. That’s ridiculous. Especially when there is this pessimistic outlook on the job market. China is a terrifying competitor, compounded by the fact that the US President is practically handing them the role of international leadership. That is the interesting part of this book though. You are presented with their insane economic success but also China’s flaws and the negative aspect of their ridiculous growth. Notably how there entire society is more “controlled”. It often seems like a Black Mirror episode. China spends more money on domestic security than national defence. Bus routes get rerouted so citizens won’t pass the courthouse when contested cases are in session. Creepy stuff. My optimism comes from the fact that the West has freedom and China doesn’t. That inevitably changes culture and behaviour of people and that is clearly illustrated in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It boils down to the fact that I am not jealous of anyone in China. The feeling of powerlessness against the ruling party is something I am terrified of and hope to never experience. The Politburo seems to have a much lower threshold than America for throwing a hood over someones head and locking them up forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just seems like the trade off wasn’t worth it. Sure your country is arguably the largest economic superpower in the world but where is your ~culture~? It just seems bland. Relevant quote from the book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let your public self be like rice in a dinner: bland and inconspicuous, taking on the flavors of its surroundings while giving off no flavor of its own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She was also moved by the way he cared for his widowed father. On their second date, he proposed marriage to her on the subway.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t bother looking for favoritism or nepotism here. Work hard, and your success will be clear in your results. Don’t bother kissing ass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d rather cry in a BMW than smile on a bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the more violent the body contact of the sports you watch, the lower the class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheung Yan,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the quantity of money passing through Macau would exceed that of Las Vegas six times over.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chinese were found to take consistently larger risks than Americans of comparable wealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Li urged us to soak our feet in hot water before bed—he said it would help with jet lag—and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Department had a breadth of authority over the realm of ideas in China that Anne-Marie Brady, a scholar who studied it, compared to the “Vatican’s influence over the Catholic world.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;until it [The Department] encompassed, by one estimate, a propaganda officer for every one hundred Chinese citizens.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was more important than ever, Party scholars pointed out, to “make their thinking conform with the dominant ideology, thereby standardizing people’s behavior.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hu Shuli had a singular profile. She was an incurable muckraker, but had cultivated first-name familiarity with some of China’s most powerful Party leaders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;mayor—and her interviewees included a promising young cadre in city government whose openness to the free market had earned him the nickname the God of Wealth. His name was Xi Jinping, and years later he would become the president of China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost nine out of ten Chinese approved of the way things were going in their country—the highest share of any of the twenty-four countries surveyed that spring by the Pew Research Center. (In the United States, by comparison, just two out of ten voiced such approval.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The United States brags about its political system, but the president says one thing during the election, something else when he takes office, something else at midterm, and something else when he leaves.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, the culture of the Web was an almost perfect opposite of the culture of the Communist Party: Chinese leaders cherished solemnity, conformity, and secrecy; the Web sanctified informality, newness, and, above all, disclosure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Authenticity, or the appearance of it, had become the rarest of assets in China.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the Party praised “democracy,” it meant “democratic centralism,” the concept of debate within its own ranks, and unquestioning adherence to final decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the instinct to shield the public from unflattering facts was absurdly at odds with the openness and sophistication in other parts of Chinese life, and it seemed to cheapen what ordinary Chinese people had worked so hard to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The night before his trial, his lawyer was detained; Chen was represented by court-appointed attorneys, who called no witnesses. He was found guilty of destroying property and disrupting traffic and was sentenced to four years and three months in prison.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the middle of April, human rights groups were calling it the largest crackdown on expression since Tiananmen Square two decades earlier. Two hundred people had been questioned or placed under house arrest; another thirty-five were presumed to be in detention. The list included not only old-line dissidents, but also social media celebrities and journalists.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;for the first time in history, the People’s Republic was spending more on domestic security than on foreign defense; it was devoting more money to policing and surveilling its own people than it was on defending against threats from abroad.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How much of the drama was light and how much was dark? How much was about opportunity and how much was about repression?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;why the most famous image from China in the past thirty years was not of its economic rise but of the man standing in front of the tank near Tiananmen Square.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a study found that 70 percent of Chinese social media users relied on social media as their main source of news; in America, that number was 9 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The maintenance people weren’t familiar enough with their jobs, and they didn’t want to stop the train. They didn’t dare.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;China’s most famous public works project was an ecosystem almost perfectly hospitable to corruption—opaque, unsupervised, and overflowing with cash.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;central government was worried that if he really succeeded in giving out four hundred million in bribes he would essentially have bought a government position. That’s why he was arrested.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public servants—officially earning twenty or thirty thousand dollars a year—became such frequent shoppers at Gucci and Louis Vuitton that high-end boutiques in Beijing ran out of stock whenever the National People’s Congress was in session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;in weak democracies, people paid their way into office by buying votes; in a state where there were no votes to buy, you paid the people who doled out the jobs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 2012 the richest seventy members of China’s national legislature had a net worth of almost ninety billion dollars—more than ten times the combined net worth of the entire U.S. Congress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bo Xilai looked like a movie star.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scandal was becoming the backbeat to China’s rise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;even if local bureaucrats were corrupt, its top leaders so exemplified wisdom, justice, and meritocracy that dissent and direct elections were superfluous and obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;wealth was hard for the Party to explain, so it decided not to try: within twenty-four hours, the government blocked the Bloomberg website—it would stay blocked in China for the foreseeable future—and&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It would cost the company millions in lost sales and advertising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He and his family can’t stay in China. It’s no longer safe,” she said. “Something will happen. It will look like an accident. Nobody will know what happened. He’ll just be found dead.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The New York Times relied on corporate records to calculate that in the years that Prime Minister Wen Jiabao was in office, his family amassed assets worth $2.7 billion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“When the rules favor the rule-makers, they are applied; when they do not, they are ignored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(An independent calculation put the figure at 0.61, higher than the level in Zimbabwe.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;people had a surprisingly high tolerance for the rise of the plutocracy. What they resented were the obstacles that prevented them from joining it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all, authorities executed at least fourteen yuan billionaires in the span of eight years, on charges ranging from pyramid schemes to murder for hire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outsiders were quick to imagine a sweatshop, but this explanation was not quite right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All websites are not to repost the news headlined, “UN Releases World Happiness Report, and China Ranks No. 112.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Foshan is a market town, the home of enormous open-air emporiums, one after another: Iron and Steel World and Flower and Plant World and Children’s Clothing Town, which sells enough clothes each year to dress every kid in America, twice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instantly, the story of the seventeen passersby began to spread across China, and it provoked a surge of self-recrimination. The writer Zhang Lijia asked, “How can we possibly win respect and play the role of a world leader if this is a nation with 1.4 billion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the years of the boom, people had picked up more reasons to fear the law than to trust it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How could China ever hope to invent the next big thing, the next Facebook, if it didn’t dare to let its people use this one?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city diverted bus routes to bypass the courthouse.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Beijing, some shopkeepers hung signs in their windows like this one, in English, at a restaurant: THIS SHOP DOES NOT RECEIVE THE JAPANESE, THE PHILIPPINES, THE VIETNAMESE AND DOG. In this&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Zhai Xiaobing, a man who worked at an investment fund in Beijing, tweeted a geeky joke that compared the meeting to a new apocalypse movie, he was arrested and held for three weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The windows of public buses were taped shut. The city banned pleasure boats from the lakes,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the only Tibetans at the Great Hall were members of the official Tibetan delegation, who brought news that Lhasa, their capital, had been voted “the happiest city in China”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;conducted a “Chinese Dream” survey, asking whether people supported one-party rule and believed in socialism, 80 percent of the three thousand respondents replied “no” to both questions,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/A-book-review</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/12/A-book-review</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>flights</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Boarding a flight is kinda weird.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, the AC105 has an absurd amount of people onboard. 
I wonder if the rising property value of a city can be associated with how many people regularly commute there. The correlation is present for this flight. The line to board was the longest I’ve ever seen and rent in Vancouver makes me want to cry.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While walking from the terminal to the plane in that tunnel thing, I pass by a separate door used only by business class passengers. This is the first in a series of disappointments.
As I enter the plane and recall Dante’s Divine Comedy; Inferno, Purgatory and Paradise. Though not in that order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I walk past Paradise first. What I assume to be aggressively rich people are already seated and have to endure the somewhat aggressive stares of all the lower class plebs walking past them. It this their punishment for paying such an absurd amount of money for a plane ticket? Wouldn’t they rather board after everyone else so as to avoid the awkward stares? I would.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Premium economy is after, which I suppose is Purgatory. The seats evolve from thrones to generous car seats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next is “preferred economy” which only serves to dishearten me more as I realize how low I’ve stooped to get on this plane.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That worry lasts only 5 seconds, or thirty depending on how efficient the people ahead of you are at packing the overhead compartments, until I arrive at the sea of regular economy seats.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I glance over the faces of the plebs. Given their location in the plane, they seem extraordinarily dignified and almost disgusted by their surroundings.  I can’t help but read the thoughts behind their expressions of misery: “Aren’t I special enough to be in the front?”, “Don’t I deserve it?”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A plane is a unique situation where middle to high-income people are reduced to taking common transport, like a bus. Of course, being on a plane is nothing like being on a bus, but that’s not the point. 
I’m trying to say that the type of middle-income people who don’t usually take public transportation are &lt;em&gt;forced&lt;/em&gt; to if they want to travel by air. Everyone is reduced to the same level, rid of income separation for the most part. The size of your seat is the same as your neighbour’s, no matter your background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unless you are in Purgatory or Paradise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The act of sharing space with a stranger is so uncomfortable to me that I would assume most people within their means would pay to be rid of that experience. That seems to be the problem. Our society nowadays seems hell-bent on not caring about anything and remaining distant from everyone (very general statement that I will not justify).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s why it seems weird that all these people have agreed to exist in these circumstances for five hours. Those two things don’t make sense together. 
I guess I’ve found the exact amount of value people place on their personal comfort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All that said, the actual economy class seat isn’t all that bad. I’m 5’9” and 150 lbs and can sit somewhat comfortably.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than your physical dimensions though, I think mastering the politics around seat manipulation are the key to a comfortable flight. Notably, armrest control and seat back position. My answers for both are simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of the seat back. You have every right to lean your seat back as much as you like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In some circumstances a full seat recline would be strange, as is exemplified by the passenger in front of me who is taking a nap at 45 degrees as the flight crew is walking by with lunch, but never unacceptable. The button is there for a reason and it’s stupid not to use it. There is not doubt it causes discomfort for your behind neighbour, as I am experiencing now, but that can always be somewhat alleviated with them reclining their own seat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Armrests are slightly more difficult. As in most situations, I notice that older people assume the right to them immediately. Ageism. The key here is persistence. Find a purchase on the armrest and stay there. That is assuming the middle, and most valuable position, is not taken yet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/flights</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/flights</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>aboriginal</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;facts&quot;&gt;Facts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Reserves want government funding, but no government oversight&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;No regulations exist for the elections of aboriginal leaders&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Infrastructure construction requires a detailed 5-year plan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;INAC (Indigenous and Northern Affairs Canada) is severely understaffed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“Trust Rating” odes not change with leadership changes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 14 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/indigeous</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/indigeous</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>intro</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve come to realize that I am not educated enough about most subjects for anyone to take my opinion seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I can offer is my perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is not to educate or to persuade. Only to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the &lt;em&gt;facts&lt;/em&gt; presented in any of these post are inaccurate, please send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear: On issues other than how to graduate from high school and hair care, my opinions shouldn’t be taken seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/intro</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/intro</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>interesting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;p-people-repeatedly-make-decisions-that-undermine-their-own-long-term-well-being&quot;&gt;P: People repeatedly make decisions that undermine their own long term well being.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;s-give-people-the-satisfaction-they-need-in-the-short-term-and-the-outcomes-that-want-in-the-long-term&quot;&gt;S: Give people the satisfaction they need in the short term &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the outcomes that want in the long term.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human don’t make good decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Health
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Stop smoking&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Exercise more&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Education
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Study better&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Teach better&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Learn better&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Personal Finance
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Save more money&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Nudge Unit in the UK government.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vQbhGJ1vWhHEqiSP5GWtoDDi-hoBd5OhuGNu7grNfqrNTimkB7VsohD0Ucckkvu2fyW0MrlLvQJhdBu/pubhtml?gid=1770440070&amp;amp;single=true&amp;amp;widget=true&amp;amp;headers=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading People:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Danny Kahneman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amos Tversky&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Richard Thaler&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nassim Taleb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/interesting!</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/interesting!</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>why keep talking?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two questions that I don’t know the answer to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why do we keep theorizing about why the 2016 election turned out the way it did?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why am I so much more involved in the US political system than my own?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Never has something been so publicized. This orange buffoon was somehow always on a TV. Obviously I never thought he would be elected. In fact, I would’ve bet a lot of money on him losing the primary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, then he won all of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Almost immediately after there came the speculation. It usually starts with a well-intentioned discussion of politics that devolves into people trying to justify why he won:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What is&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sexism?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Racism?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The establishment?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two party system?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Populism?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Angry middle class?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Political incorrectness?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Television presence?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Media attention?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think it was the media.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the point is WHO CARES? Until we figure out how to make a truth serum and chem trail into the lungs of every American citizen, there is not concrete way to know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main point:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-will-never-know-why-trump-won-the-2016-election&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We will never know why Trump won the 2016 election.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why keep talking?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pay more attention to US politics than I do Canadian politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naming the speaker of the house, senate majority and minority leader, secretary of state, defence, energy, education and the vice-president is easy, yet naming anyone other than Justin Trudeau in the Canadian executive branch is impossible. Is it even called an executive branch here? I don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Justifying my seemingly extreme interest in US politics is difficult. Am I engaged because these policies and changes in leadership could affect my own life? No. Although they may have a vague effect on me, it is unreasonable to think that anything other than a declaration of war by the US would be directly relevant to me. 
That is not to say that US politics are not relevant to me &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;, the point is that there are &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; more relevant things I could be paying attention to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real reason why I pay an unreasonable amount of attention to US politics is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;It’s entertainment that makes you feel smart.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Almost all of what I pay attention to will not affect me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I rarely learn more than the headline, and almost never delve into the actually policy at hand.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More often than not, I do not learn anything from the news.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I learn on a week to week basis is basically the equivalent of a Stephen Colbert monologue. I remember the headlines, forget the policy and get some entertainment out of the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question: Why don’t I follow Canadian politics just as attentively?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answer: The US has a sophisticated media infrastructure built around making politics entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before it was the president’s &lt;em&gt;intent&lt;/em&gt; to be entertaining, the media made politics entertaining on its own. Remember Obama’s Khaki suit? Or the birth certificate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why doesn’t Canada have the same entertainment infrastructure? Where is our Stephen Colbert monologue making fun of Justin Trudeau’s socks or something?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reasons why there isn’t entertainment focused around Canadian politics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The events happening aren’t as exciting?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People in Canada are not interested in politics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are less people in general, less potential viewers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidenote: The first reason might cause the following one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A misconception is that an audience for Canadian politics doesn’t exist. If the way the news is presented is entertaining, an audience will develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example #1: me. Why am I consuming so much US political news? Because of the way it is presented. There is almost no logical reason why I should be as engaged as I am in the Virginia Governor’s Race, but I’m refreshing the polls right now all the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forms of media about politics that I consume:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;podcasts&quot;&gt;Podcasts&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pod Save America&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Ezra Klein Show&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This American Life&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Revisionist History&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;On The Media&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Stay Tuned&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;youtube&quot;&gt;Youtube&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Phillip Defranco&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;John Oliver&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Stephen Colbert&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Samantha Bee&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Seth Myers&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;news&quot;&gt;News&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reddit&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Vox&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;the Economist&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Five Thirty Eight&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continued,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or deleted???&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/why-keep-talking</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/why-keep-talking</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>on the timelessness of skateboarding</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;this is just here to remind me to write about this&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/on-the-timeless-beauty-of-skateboarding</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/10/on-the-timeless-beauty-of-skateboarding</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>on vlogging and its dangerous applications</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The combining of your personal and professional life would probably suck right?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/on-vlogging-and-its-dangerous-implications</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/10/on-vlogging-and-its-dangerous-implications</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>internet dialogues</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Don’t try to argue with someone on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sorry im gonna finish this someday&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/internet-dialogues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/09/internet-dialogues</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>stock market</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
After spending 18 years of my life idolizing rich investement bankers on Wall Street, I have come to a brutal realization:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most investing is gambling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I realized this after reading Nassim Taleb’s book, Fooled by Randomness. To summarize, Taleb proves that behaviours like hindsight bias and pattern-seeking are widely prevalent in today’s society, especially in the investment banking sector. Often, bankers are victim to completely random occurrences in the market, yet attribute them to “skill” and “foresight”. I wrote a bit about this:
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;A striking example of this behaviour is the justification for the start of World War 1. As was drilled into me in high school, the assassination of Franz Ferdinand and the escalating tension and militarization in various countries predicted this international conflict. The ensuing World War seems to have been inevitable - after the events have transpired. This is an example of hindsight bias. As Niall Ferguson, a professor of history at Harvard, makes clear in his paper &lt;em&gt;The international bond market between the 1848 revolution and the outbreak of the First World War&lt;/em&gt;, war bond prices were steady. The world had not noticed these so-called significant events. &lt;b&gt;If these hints towards the upcoming conflict were as clear as we now make them out to be, why did the price of war bonds not rise?&lt;/b&gt; Was there a sudden, universal lack of desire to make profit? or were the events we speak of today not obvious at all. Clearly, the latter is more in line with human nature. We feel the need to justify events after the fact in order to reassure ourselves that we will see it coming next time.
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;matthew counts as more evidence for this point
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://kahvipatel.com/Media/nobody2.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Small example image&quot; title=&quot;nobody2&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can never win against a computer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It take a human about 300-400 milliseconds to blink. Currently, it takes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/091615/world-high-frequency-algorithmic-trading.asp&quot;&gt;High Frequency Trading Firms&lt;/a&gt; (basically computers that trade stocks) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/602135/high-frequency-trading-is-nearing-the-ultimate-speed-limit/&quot;&gt;85 nanoseconds&lt;/a&gt; to execute a trade. To put that into perspective, in the time it take you to blink your eye, &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; HFT computer could execute 3.5 million trades. Basically, computers are just alot faster that you are.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unpredictable in the short term, predictable in the long term: The only certain way to make money in the stock market is over time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://awealthofcommonsense.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/SPX-Time-Frames.png&quot; alt=&quot;Small example image&quot; title=&quot;investing chart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
^if you invest in an S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF, you can basically flip a coin to see whether you will make money tommorow. In a decade though, you have a much higher chance of profit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
okay, here’s a research paper
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Kahvi Patel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Research Paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Tutorial 9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;April 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2017&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Tutor: S. Boos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;In the early 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century, the separation between scientific and non-scientific theories was vague. The most practical way to distinguish a theory as scientific was to determine whether it was known a posteriori; relied on an empirical method. This meant that astrology, given its vast amounts of observed information, qualified as a scientific theory. In 1919, Karl Popper sought to contrive an alternative separation. Falsifiability was the philosophical term he coined. With this theory, Popper set the groundwork for the modern scientific method and, simultaneously, addressed the problem of induction that had troubled Hume and many other philosophers before him. Popper’s theory of Falsification, however, not only has its roots in philosophy, but in human nature. As has been the case throughout history, human nature is more prone towards what Popper distinguished as “pseudo-scientific” theories rather than “scientific” ones. Our inherent desires are what make Popper’s theory of Falsification especially relevant; Demarcation is a tool to fight against our own misleading natural instincts. In order to repress this widespread malpractice, we must employ tactics of doubt exemplified by philosophers like Descartes and Socrates in order to enforce a more logical, and therefore more productive, general consciousness. As Popper originally described in his theory, falsification, rather than confirmation, must be what we seek in order to prove our own theories.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;For Popper, the reason for distinguishing between theories was not for lack of truth; “it was not my doubting the truth of those other…theories which bothered me, but something else” (Popper 32). Neither was it because of the different nature of some theories or the variability in accuracy they provided. In fact, what bothered Popper were the incessant “confirming instances” relating to the “pseudo-scientific theories” in question. Freud’s theory of psychoanalysis, for example, was supported repeatedly by whatever the psychologist theorized. In other words, every event confirmed the theory. This practice has a flaw.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;I may illustrate this by two very different examples of human behavior: that of a man who pushes a child into the water with the intention of drowning it; and that of a man who sacrifices his life in an attempt to save the child. Each of these two cases can be explained with equal ease in Freudian and in Adlerian terms. According to Freud the first man suffered from repression (say, of some component of his Oedipus complex), while the second man had achieved sublimation. According to Adler the first man suffered fro feelings of inferiority (producing perhaps the need to prove to himself that he dared to commit some crime), and so did the second man (whose need was to prove to himself that he dared to rescue the child). (Popper 35)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;This situation demonstrates the ambiguity of Freud’s (and Adler’s) theory. The result, no matter how unexpected or crazy, can always be justified. This method was in direct contrast to another Popper had witnessed; Einstein’s theory of gravitation. Whereas Freud’s theory relied on explanation, Einstein’s relied on prediction. More specifically, one sought confirmation, the other sought falsification. Alarmingly though, both relied on empirical evidence and the method of induction, thus classifying them both, for now, as scientific theories. Importantly, Popper did not attempt to discredit the validity of Freud’s theory, although he may have done so unconsciously. His intention was merely to distinguish it. The significance of this separation cannot be understated. As history progressed, a scientific method was developed around Popper’s falsifiability and a distinguishable separation began to emerge between science and others things.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;More than just a method for distinction between theories, Falsification has significance in human behavior. In general, humans are programmed to ignore events that do not agree with their beliefs and pay attentions to ones that do. This behavior is called confirmation bias. Unfortunately, it has been proven to exist throughout many studies, the most famous of which is the Wason Selection Task.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;He presented subjects with the three-number sequence 2, 4, 6, and asked them to try to guess the rule generating it. Their method of guessing was to produce other three-number sequences, to which the experimenter would respond “yes” or “no” depending on whether the new sequences were consistent with the rule. Once confident with their answers, the subjects would formulate the rule. The correct rule was “numbers in ascending order,” nothing more. Very few subjects discovered it because in order to do so they had to offer a series in descending order (that the experimenter would say “no” to). (Taleb 123)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;This experiment demonstrates our inherent instinct to always seek confirmation for our own hypothesis, or theories, instead or trying to discredit them. Once the subjects had formulated a rule, their only intention became trying to find a pattern that fit it instead of trying to supply a series that was inconsistent with their hypothesis. Our natural human behavior compels us to seek confirmation. The parallels here are widespread. Today, most people gather their information (and biases) from the news. And there is more news today than ever before. The constant news cycle compounds biases. People have access to countless sources of evidence, or “number series”, which they use to confirm their own opinions. It becomes much more difficult to attempt to disprove your own opinion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;A most poignant example of this behavior of confirmation bias is the political polarization that currently exists in the United States: both sides seek confirmation for their own theories, never falsification. Popper’s Demarcation seems to work against human instinct. For instance, Freud’s theory of psychoanalysis is more easily understandable than Einstein’s theory of gravity and thus more attractive. This inherent preference leads to many human patterns of behavior, such as illusion of control and hindsight bias. When a need to explain something arises, we are predisposed to justify our theory by seeking confirmation instead of testing it. &lt;b&gt;A striking example of this behavior is the justification for the start of World War 1. Clearly, the assassination of Franz Ferdinand and the escalating tension and militarization in various countries might predict international conflict. The ensuing World War seems to have been inevitable - after the events have transpired. This is an example of hindsight bias which generates pseudo-scientific theories. As Niall Ferguson, a professor of history at Harvard, makes clear in his paper &lt;em&gt;The international bond market between the 1848 revolution and the outbreak of the First World War&lt;/em&gt;, the world had not noticed these so-called significant events, as evidenced by the flat lining of war bond prices. If these hints towards the upcoming conflict were as clear as we now make them out to be, why did the price of war bonds not rise? Was there a sudden, universal lack of desire to make profit? or were the events we speak of today not obvious at all. Clearly, the latter is more in line with human nature. The pseudo-scientific theory suggests that the war started because of an episode of tension and militarization. This is an example of seeking confirmation and hindsight bias. We feel the need to justify events after the fact in order to reassure ourselves that we will see it coming next time.&lt;/b&gt; More often than not, however, our theories for the cause of past events are vulnerable to falsification. Until those theories in question can withstand falsification, this practice of explanation is useless.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Our constant desire to fabricate an illusion of control leads us to justify theories in unreliable ways. When theories are not tested with falsification, they can lead us to misleading conclusions or a false sense of security. In 470 BC, Socrates exposed society’s wrongful act of gathering, spreading and reciting knowledge that had illogical grounds. In what we now call “Socratic Dialogue”, Socrates reduced his subject’s opinions to a single thesis which was often illogical. Through this, he proved the Delphi’s prophecy true: he was, in fact, “the wisest of men”. This title, however, did not originate from vast education or far-reaching experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;I am wiser than this man; it is likely that neither of us knows anything worthwhile, but he thinks he knows something when he does not, whereas when I do not know, neither do I think I know; so I am likely to be wiser than he to this small extent, that I do not think I know what I do not know. (Plato 3)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Socrates was merely the only man who knew the extent of his own ignorance. Today, we encounter a similar situation. Many of our generally accepted theories and personal opinions are illogical and/or justified by a flawed method. More importantly though, the vast majority of society &lt;em&gt;does not realize&lt;/em&gt; this. Descartes provides another apt exemplar. His doubt, though undoubtedly extreme, was important to build a foundation of truth upon which the rest of his beliefs were founded.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot; name=&quot;GoBack&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;It is as though they [my beliefs] had a right to a place in my belief-system as a result of long occupation and the law of custom. These habitual opinions of mine are indeed highly probable; although they are in a sense doubtful, as I have shown, it is more reasonable to believe than to deny them. But if I go on viewing them in that light I shall never get out of the habit of confidently assenting to them. To conquer that habit, therefore, I had better switch right around and pretend (for a while) that these former opinions of mine are utterly false and imaginary. I shall do this until I have something to counter-balance the weight of old opinion, and the distorting influence of habit no longer prevents me from judging correctly. (Descartes 2)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;The important parallel here is doubt. To doubt one’s own belief is the most basic and true form of falsification. We must draw from influences of the past to create a better future. We must take advice from Socrates and Descartes and question our own theories and opinions in order to arrive at the roots of our beliefs. We must acknowledge our own ignorance in order to take the next step towards progress.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Popper’s philosophy was originally meant to distinguish scientific theories. His philosophy of Demarcation, however, went beyond science, and addressed two methods of thinking. Unfortunately for humanity, we are prone to the less reliable mode of thinking: one that seeks confirmation. This behavior has led to a worrying trend in human history. By analyzing the past and present, we may understand how hindsight bias and the illusion of control reveal themselves in society and how they are the result of instinctual human behavior. With the problem assessed and recognized, we may understand it and endeavor to solve it. Turning to philosophers of the past, such as Descartes and Socrates, helps us recognize the underlying theme of doubt in their work and leads us to an apt solution. Doubt is perhaps the truest form of falsification and should be practiced by individuals today in order to help justify beliefs. The practice of seeking to falsify one’s own beliefs takes courage and determination but is ultimately the path towards a more reliable future. Unless we begin challenging our beliefs, instead of seeking confirmation of them, moral progress will slow. If we begin using Popper’s method in our lives, diversity of opinion and success will be the result.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Works Cited&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Popper, Karl. &lt;em&gt;Conjectures and Refutations&lt;/em&gt;. Basic Books, 1962.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Nicholas Taleb, Nassim. &lt;em&gt;The Black Swan: The Impact of the Highly Improbable.&lt;/em&gt; Random House, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Ferguson, Niall. “Political risk and the international bond market between the 1848 revolution and the outbreak of the First World War.” &lt;em&gt;Economic History Review&lt;/em&gt;, Vol 29, no. 1, February 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Plato. &lt;em&gt;Apology&lt;/em&gt;. translated by G.M.A. Grube, Hackett Publishing Company, 2000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Descartes, Renee. &lt;em&gt;Meditations on First Philosophy&lt;/em&gt;. translated by Jonathan F. Bennett, Cambridge University Press, 1996.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
inspired by Nassim Nicholas Taleb and &lt;a href=&quot;http://jamesclear.com/book-summaries/fooled-by-randomness&quot;&gt;Fooled by Randomness&lt;/a&gt; (great read)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/stock-market</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/07/stock-market</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
