<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kahvi's blog</title>
    <description>I create here sometimes. And rarely captalize.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 14:51:35 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 14:51:35 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>position paper</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been going through old papers of mine recently and this one struck me as actually interesting enough to share. I wrote a barebones &lt;a href=&quot;/2017/11/on-behavioural-economics&quot;&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; on this subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;academic&quot;&gt;Kahvi Patel&lt;br /&gt;
Research Paper&lt;br /&gt;
April 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;academic indent&quot;&gt;In the early 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century, the separation between scientific and non-scientific theories was vague. The most practical way to distinguish a theory as scientific was to determine whether it was known a posteriori; relied on an empirical method. This meant that astrology, given its vast amounts of observed information, qualified as a scientific theory. In 1919, Karl Popper sought to contrive an alternative separation. Falsifiability was the philosophical term he coined. With this theory, Popper set the groundwork for the modern scientific method and, simultaneously, addressed the problem of induction that had troubled Hume and many other philosophers before him. Popper’s theory of Demarcation, however, not only has its roots in philosophy, but in human nature. As has been the case throughout history, human nature is more prone towards what Popper distinguished as “pseudo-scientific” theories rather than “scientific” ones. Our inherent desires are what make Popper’s theory of Falsification especially relevant; Demarcation is a tool to fight against our own misleading instincts. In order to repress this widespread malpractice, we must employ tactics of doubt exemplified by philosophers like Descartes and Socrates in order to enforce a more logical, and therefore more productive, general consciousness. As Popper originally described in his theory, &lt;em&gt;we must seek falsification&lt;/em&gt;, or doubt, &lt;em&gt;rather than confirmation&lt;/em&gt; in order to prove our own theories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;academic indent&quot;&gt;For Popper, the reason for distinguishing between theories was not “ doubting the &lt;em&gt;truth&lt;/em&gt; of those other theories, but something else” (Popper 32). What bothered Popper were the incessant “confirming instances” relating to the “pseudo-scientific theories” in question. Freud’s theory of psychoanalysis, for example, was supported repeatedly by whatever the psychologist theorized. In other words, &lt;em&gt;every event confirmed the theory&lt;/em&gt;. This practice has a flaw.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote class=&quot;academic&quot;&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I may illustrate this by two very different examples of human behavior: that of a man who pushes a child into the water with the intention of drowning it; and that of a man who sacrifices his life in an attempt to save the child. Each of these two cases can be explained with equal ease in Freudian and in Adlerian terms. According to Freud the first man suffered from repression (say, of some component of his Oedipus complex), while the second man had achieved sublimation. According to Adler the first man suffered from feelings of inferiority (producing perhaps the need to prove to himself that he dared to commit some crime), and so did the second man (whose need was to prove to himself that he dared to rescue the child). (Popper 35)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;academic&quot;&gt;This situation demonstrates the ambiguity of Freud’s (and Adler’s) theory. The result, no matter how unexpected or crazy, can always be justified. This method was in direct contrast to another Popper had witnessed; Einstein’s theory of gravitation. Whereas Freud’s theory relied on explanation, Einstein’s relied on prediction. More specifically, one sought &lt;em&gt;confirmation&lt;/em&gt;, the other sought &lt;em&gt;falsification&lt;/em&gt;. Alarmingly though, both relied on empirical evidence and the method of induction, thus classing them both, for now, as scientific theories. Importantly, Popper did not attempt to discredit the validity of Freud’s theory, although he may have done so unconsciously. His intention was merely to distinguish it. The significance of this separation cannot be understated. As history progressed, a scientific method was developed around Popper’s falsifiability and a separation began to emerge between science and others things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;academic indent&quot;&gt;More than just a method for distinction between theories, Falsification has significance in human behavior. In general, humans are programmed to ignore events that do not agree with their beliefs and pay attentions to ones that do. This behavior is called &lt;em&gt;confirmation bias&lt;/em&gt; and has been proven to exist in many studies, the most famous of which is the Wason Selection Task. Feel free to attempt this experiment on friends.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;academic&quot;&gt;He presented subjects with the three-number sequence 2, 4, 6, and asked them to try and guess the rule generating it. Their method of guessing was to produce other three-number sequences, to which the experimenter would respond &amp;ldquo;yes&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; depending on whether the new sequences were consistent with the rule. Once confident with their answers, the subjects would formulate the rule. The correct rule was &amp;ldquo;numbers in ascending order,&amp;rdquo; nothing more. Very few subjects discovered it because in order to do so they had to offer a series in descending order (that the experimenter would say &amp;ldquo;no&amp;rdquo; to). (Taleb 123)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;academic&quot;&gt;This experiment demonstrates our inherent instinct to always seek confirmation for our own hypothesis, or theories, instead or trying to discredit them. Once the subjects had formulated a rule, their only intention became trying to find a pattern that fit it instead of trying to supply a series that was &lt;em&gt;inconsistent&lt;/em&gt; with their hypothesis. Our natural human behavior compels us to seek confirmation. The parallels here are widespread. Today, most people gather their information (and biases) from the news and there is more news today than ever before. The constant news cycle compounds biases. People have access to countless sources of evidence, or &quot;number series&quot;, which they use to confirm their own opinions. It becomes much more difficult to attempt to disprove your own opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;academic indent&quot;&gt;A most poignant example of this behavior of confirmation bias is the political polarization that currently exists in the United States: both sides seek confirmation for their own theories, never falsification. Popper&amp;rsquo;s Demarcation seems to work against human instinct. For instance, Freud&amp;rsquo;s theory of psychoanalysis is more easily understandable than Einstein&amp;rsquo;s theory of gravity and thus more attractive. This inherent preference leads to many human patterns of behavior, such as illusion of control and hindsight bias. When a need to explain something arises, we are predisposed to justify our theory by seeking confirmation instead of testing it. A striking example of this behavior is the justification for the start of World War 1. Clearly, the assassination of Franz Ferdinand and the escalating tension and militarization in various countries might predict international conflict. The ensuing World War seems to have been &lt;em&gt;inevitable&lt;/em&gt; - after the events have transpired. This is an example of hindsight bias. As Niall Ferguson, a professor of history at Harvard, makes clear in his paper &lt;em&gt;The international bond market between the 1848 revolution and the outbreak of the First World War&lt;/em&gt;, the world had not noticed these so-called significant events, as evidenced by the flat lining of war bond prices. &lt;strong&gt;If these hints towards the upcoming conflict were as clear as we now make them out to be, why did the price of war bonds not rise? &lt;/strong&gt;Was there a sudden, universal lack of desire to make profit? or were the events we speak of today &lt;em&gt;not obvious at all&lt;/em&gt;. Clearly, the latter is more in line with human nature. The pseudo-scientific theory suggests that the war started because of an episode of tension and militarization. We feel the need to justify events after the fact in order to reassure ourselves that we will see it coming next time. Yet, until those theories in question can withstand falsification, this practice of explanation is useless.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;academic indent&quot;&gt;When theories are not tested with falsification, they can lead us to misleading conclusions or a false sense of security. In 470 BC, Socrates exposed society&amp;rsquo;s wrongful act of gathering, spreading and reciting knowledge that had illogical grounds. In what we now call &amp;ldquo;Socratic Dialogue&amp;rdquo;, Socrates reduced his subject&amp;rsquo;s opinions to a single thesis which was often illogical. Through this, he proved the Delphi&amp;rsquo;s prophecy true: he was, in fact, &amp;ldquo;the wisest of men&amp;rdquo;. This title, however, did not originate from vast education or far-reaching experience.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;academic&quot;&gt;I am wiser than this man; it is likely that neither of us knows anything worthwhile, but he thinks he knows something when he does not, whereas when I do not know, neither do I think I know; so I am likely to be wiser than he to this small extent, that &lt;em&gt;I do not think I know what I do not know&lt;/em&gt;. (Plato 3)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;academic&quot;&gt;Socrates was merely the only man who knew the extent of his own ignorance. Today, we encounter a similar situation. Many of our generally accepted theories and personal opinions are illogical and/or justified by a flawed method. More importantly though, the vast majority of society &lt;em&gt;does not realize&lt;/em&gt; this. Descartes provides another apt exemplar. His doubt, though undoubtedly extreme, was important to build a foundation of truth upon which the rest of his beliefs were founded.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p class=&quot;academic&quot;&gt;It is as though they [my beliefs] had a right to a place in my belief-system as a result of long occupation and the law of custom. These habitual opinions of mine are indeed highly probable; although they are in a sense doubtful, as I have shown, it is more reasonable to believe than to deny them. But if I go on viewing them in that light I shall never get out of the habit of confidently assenting to them. To conquer that habit, therefore, I had better switch right around and pretend (for a while) that these former opinions of mine are utterly false and imaginary. I shall do this until I have something to counter-balance the weight of old opinion, and the distorting influence of habit no longer prevents me from judging correctly. (Descartes 2)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;academic&quot;&gt;The important parallel here is doubt. To doubt one&amp;rsquo;s own belief is the most basic and true form of falsification. We must take advice from Socrates and Descartes and question our own theories and opinions in order to arrive at the roots of our beliefs. We must acknowledge our own ignorance in order to take the next step towards progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;academic indent&quot;&gt;Popper&amp;rsquo;s philosophy was originally meant to distinguish scientific theories. His philosophy of Demarcation, however, went beyond science, and addressed two methods of thinking. Unfortunately for humanity, we are prone to the less reliable mode of thinking: one that seeks confirmation. This behavior has led to a worrying trend in human history. By analyzing the past and present, we may understand how hindsight bias and the illusion of control reveal themselves in society and how they are the result of instinctual human behavior. With the problem assessed and recognized, we may understand it and endeavor to solve it. Doubt is perhaps the truest form of falsification and should be practiced by individuals today in order to justify beliefs. Unless we begin challenging our beliefs, instead of seeking confirmation of them, progress of all kinds will slow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;academic&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Works Cited&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul class=&quot;academic&quot;&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Popper, Karl. &lt;em&gt;Conjectures and Refutations&lt;/em&gt;. Basic Books, 1962. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nicholas Taleb, Nassim. &lt;em&gt;The Black Swan: The Impact of the Highly&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Improbable.&amp;lt;/em&amp;gt; Random House, 2007.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ferguson, Niall. “Political risk and the international bond market between the 1848 revolution and the outbreak of the First World War.” &lt;em&gt;Economic History Review&lt;/em&gt;, Vol 29, no. 1, February 2006.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plato. &lt;em&gt;Apology&lt;/em&gt;. translated by G.M.A. Grube, Hackett Publishing Company, 2000.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Descartes, Renee. &lt;em&gt;Meditations on First Philosophy&lt;/em&gt;. translated by Jonathan F. Bennett, Cambridge University Press, 1996.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/09/position-paper</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/09/position-paper</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>my youtube channel</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/user/techkid105&quot;&gt;youtube channel&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s been fun posting videos. A more involved form of self-expression than instagram.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have ones about &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/yli2zN2mV4M&quot;&gt;sailing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/_Bn3N3SI2-o&quot;&gt;skiing&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/4acqZOnjB70&quot;&gt;skating&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/ftmrS3Eg2-I&quot;&gt;skating&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;https://youtu.be/8iYcGz_nrj8&quot;&gt;scrambled eggs&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m only now realizing the alliteration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One lesson learned: &lt;strong&gt;the edit is all that matters&lt;/strong&gt;. For me, 90% of the effort is put in during the edit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/07/youtube</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/07/youtube</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>us ideology</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This one gets into political ideology which I don’t usually like to talk about.
Spending a few days in and around Chicago has illustrated to me the constant, uncomfortable tension in American society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To begin, Canada is not that different from America. Obviously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If money is our objective measure of success, Canada is failing. Our dollar is weaker. Is the mentality behind the US economy the right one? So often it’s painted as an abstract idea of perseverance and determination over everything. Seeing this in effect is less simple.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We use money as our objective measure of success because that’s what everyone else uses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The stress I see around Chicago is not unlike the one that exists in Kingston. There are wealthy areas and not wealth areas. What disturbs me is the scale to which this applies in America. It’s either poor or rich.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read this in every headline: The middle class is disappearing. It’s really harsh to see the reality reflect those headlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Everything that’s big is bigger. Everything that’s small is smaller. Everyone that’s rich is richer, everyone that’s poor is poorer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(This is me dumming an incredible complex issue down to an easily digestible couple sentences that sound the same to make it easier to convince you of my perspective)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But the difficulty is that people want it that way. The mentality is all or nothing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You wonder why so many people fall into that trap of inflated optimism. I’m a victim to it. I think my future will be brighter than it should be. It’s a country of idealists. With no facts to go around. And their infrastructure is shitty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The mentality is confusing. For there to be winners, there have to be losers. Yet the losers think they’re all winners in the making and the winners keep convincing reinforcing that false belief.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/07/us-ideology</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/07/us-ideology</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>on gladwell</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Background: Malcolm Gladwell hosts a &lt;a href=&quot;http://revisionisthistory.com/seasons?selected=season-3&quot;&gt;podcast&lt;/a&gt;, he did an episode on CTE today. Chronic traumatic encephalopathy (CTE) is the reason everyone is scared of football these days: Head trauma leads a bunch of bad stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;His thesis, basically, is: “At what point do you have enough proof to act?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a speech given at UPenn in 2013, Gladwell uses the example of coal miners in the 1940s. Coal was an integral part of the economy back then; many working class families were supported by the industry. There were drawbacks though. Namely, workers would cough up black coal dust and generally cough a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For various reasons, people said the coughing was a sign of the respiratory system working &lt;em&gt;correctly&lt;/em&gt; and did not consider negative health impacts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then a statistician came along and &lt;strong&gt;proved&lt;/strong&gt; that inhaling coal dust all day was very bad for you and reduces your life expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here, in his speech, Malcolm asks the audience “What do you think happened then?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“&lt;em&gt;Nothing&lt;/em&gt;” he answers dramatically (it was a rhetorical question).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wasn’t until 1975 that a general consensus was reached about the dangers of coal mining and action was taken.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gladwell’s parallel is with football today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He goes on to argue that the students at UPenn should boycott the school’s football game in protest of the University ignoring proof.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;i-have-a-problem-with-his-argument-though&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have a problem with his argument though.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If an adult is aware of the risks of an activity and is not harming others in the process, what right do we have to stop them?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question has little to do with football, yet is the core of Gladwell’s argument. &lt;em&gt;Every sport&lt;/em&gt; has different degrees of good and bad depending on who you ask.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The key insight is that the people participating should be the ones to weigh the pros and cons, not us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Society should do everything in its power to provide information to judge the sport with (like studies about CTE), but the &lt;em&gt;decisions made&lt;/em&gt; based on that information are &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; in society’s control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This idea of athletes taking this decision into their own hands was never addressed in the podcast. Instead, athletes were only mentioned when the consequences of &lt;em&gt;their&lt;/em&gt; actions befell &lt;em&gt;them&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Malcolm strays away from this moral question, or purposefully ignores it, because it is harder to answer than the one he asks in his podcast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reducing this issue down to right and wrong is reductive and demeans the judgment of football players/responsible adults.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 28 May 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/05/on-gladwell</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/05/on-gladwell</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>on statistics</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.amazon.com/Naked-Statistics-Stripping-Dread-Data/dp/1480590185&quot;&gt;Naked Statistics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sidenote: &lt;em&gt;This post is based entirely on what I’ve learned while reading ^that book.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three concepts in statistics that are important to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;1-law-of-large-numbers&quot;&gt;1. Law of Large Numbers&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“An important theorem known as the law of large numbers tells us that as the number of trials increases, the average of the outcomes will get closer and closer to its expected value”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is counter intuitive. This is how I think of this theory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You are flipping a coin 10 times. Imagine the first eight times you flip the coin, it lands on heads. Intuitively, you would assume that the next flip is more likely to land on tails than heads. This is FALSE.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time you flip the coin, nothing different is happening. Every flip is a 50/50 chance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of your 10 flips, you have landed nine heads and one tail. This doesn’t make sense. If the likelihood of flipping both possibilities is equal, why is the outcome so skewed?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because you have witnessed an anomaly. The chances of you hitting nine heads in a row are very small (1/512 or 0.2%). The results you have witnessed are not representative of the true probability.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The true probability only emerges as you keep flipping the coin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The logic behind this is hard to understand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, the more time you flip the coin, the less anomalies (like nine heads in a row) will matter to the overall result. Eventually anomalies are drowned out and the true probability can be seen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The chart below illustrates the theory. Every flip, the average of heads is calculated: (number of head flips / total number of flips). According to everything that makes sense, that number should be 0.5 or 1/2.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/heads14.png&quot; alt=&quot;Coin Flip Chart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over the first 10 trials, the average number of heads fluctuates wildly, from an underrepresentation to an overrepresentation in 10 flips. You can see how if we stopped after just 10 flips, it would be hard to draw a conclusion about the &lt;em&gt;true probability&lt;/em&gt; of this situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As more coins are flipped though, the average number of heads move closer to 0.5, which is what probability says it should be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The law of large numbers explains why casinos always make money in the long run. The probabilities associated with all casino games favor the house (assuming that the casino can successfully prevent blackjack players from counting cards). If enough bets are wagered over a long enough time, the casino will be certain to win more than it loses.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wheelan, Charles. “Naked Statistics: Stripping the Dread from the Data.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2-independent-and-dependent-relations&quot;&gt;2. Independent and Dependent Relations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time a coin is flipped heads, the chance of the second flip being heads stays exactly the same. This is called an independent relation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time a car is parked, the chance of the driver getting a parking ticket increases. This is a dependent relation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Often, we do not realize what event are independent and dependent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The classic example is a “hot-hand” in basketball. After a player makes a certain amount of shots in a row, it seems more likely that he will make the next shot. We assume that this is a dependent relation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.sciencedirect.com/science/article/pii/0010028585900106&quot;&gt;It isn’t&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;3-percentages&quot;&gt;3. Percentages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More often than not, a percentage is a better way to understand data than an absolute number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When looking at a storefront, I would rather know what &lt;em&gt;percentage&lt;/em&gt; of the price is discounted than an absolute number. Saving $5 on a $10 item is awesome, but saving $5 on a $200 item is shitty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When looking at a company, I would rather know a &lt;em&gt;percentage&lt;/em&gt; for revenue growth rather than an absolute number. Growing yearly revenues from $20 billion to $20.1 billion is not a huge difference, but $100 million in additional revenue &lt;em&gt;sounds&lt;/em&gt; great.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Percentages give you context for absolute numbers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, we should address some fallacies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Assume that a department store is selling a dress for $100. The assistant manager marks down all merchandise by 25 percent. But then that assistant manager is fired…and the new assistant manager raises all prices by 25 percent. What is the final price of the dress? If you said (or thought) $100, ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then you are wrong. Here is what happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The price was originally $100. Then it was discounted by 25%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25% of $100 is, clearly, $25. Therefore, the new price is $100 - $25 = $75.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then the price was raised by 25%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;25% of $75 is $18.75. Therefore, the new price is $75 + $18.75 = $93.75.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concept is especially important in the stock market:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say you buy $50 of Apple stock on Monday. The stock goes down 12% on Tuesday, but then goes up 12% on Wednesday. You do not start Thursday with $50 of Apple stock. You will have less.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The Democrats, who engineered this tax increase, pointed out (correctly) that the state income tax rate was increased by 2 percentage points (from 3 percent to 5 percent). The Republicans pointed out (also correctly) that the state income tax had been raised by 67 percent.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This example&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://citeseerx.ist.psu.edu/viewdoc/download?doi=10.1.1.479.3099&amp;amp;rep=rep1&amp;amp;type=pdf&quot;&gt;Luck versus Skill in the Cross-Section of Mutual Fund Returns&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 09 May 2018 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/05/on-statistics</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/05/on-statistics</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>my book list</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Preface: Reading a book requires so much of my attention that I never finish books that do not interest me. Therefore, I would honestly recommend all the books listed below. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This list will be updated continuously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the &lt;a href=&quot;/bookhighlights.html&quot;&gt;highlights&lt;/a&gt; from all the books I’ve read on the Kindle (I’m really bad at updating this).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-this-year-&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt; this year &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The English Patient&lt;br /&gt;
Not sure how I got through this book. It has exciting moments, but they are few and far between. This book takes a certain type of focus and patience that I barely have. It’s rewarding by the end though. About a group of people who live in an Italian villa after the War. Explores each of their historiy, some more than others.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Brief and Wondrous Life of Oscar Wao&lt;br /&gt;
Fun book to read. It goes by fast mostly due to the narrator’s hilarious tone. Follows a family through three generations as they navigate the Dominican Republic and then the United States, but mostly about Oscar Wao. Left me with a melancholy feeling. Important tip: Do not read the introduction, it takes way too long and is discouraging. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Idiot &lt;br /&gt;
This book is dense. It took me a while to finish. I haven’t encountered this type of writing style before. It’s abrupt and unique. I identify with the main character and her setting deeply. &lt;a href=&quot;/_pages/highlights/The-Idiot&quot;&gt;Highlights here&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;La Belle Sauvage &lt;br /&gt;
I had a vague memory of liking the &lt;em&gt;Golden Compass&lt;/em&gt; trilogy by the same author (Philip Pullman), which is why I read this book. It took me by surprise. The shift of environment and tone after the first half was sudden, but grew on me. One of my favourite main characters in any book. This story carries with it some deeper moral lessons. Set in a similar world as Harry Potter, but more serious and &lt;em&gt;slightly&lt;/em&gt; less supernatural.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2018/05/on-statistics.html&quot;&gt;Naked Statistics&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
Until reading this book, I never had a grasp on statistics. I’ve now realized how important it is. The nature of statistics is counter-intuitive and learning the a few important concepts means defeating misinformation in your daily life. It’s dense though.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Obelisk Gate &lt;br /&gt;
The second book in the Broken Earth series. Just as engaging as the first. Sped through this book in two days.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Fifth Season &lt;br /&gt;
I devoured this book. The first in the Broken Earth series. Starts out rough, but keeps you trapped till the end. The first time in a while I’ve actually been enthralled with fantasy.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Death’s End &lt;br /&gt;
A fitting end to an amazing trilogy. This book dives even deeper into fantasy and I believe it completely every step of the way. Contains the most realistic view of our (humanity’s) future, I think.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Dark Forest &lt;br /&gt;
The book is better than the first (The Three-Body Problem) in the trilogy. Takes a while to get started, but it’s an amazing ride once it does. If you are at all interested in alien life or astrophysics please read this book.&lt;br /&gt;
The idea of a “dark forest” is so overarching and terrifying that it my changed my perception of space.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Three-Body Problem (re-read) &lt;br /&gt;
My second favourite science-fiction novel. Involves the Chinese Cultural Revolution, chaotic motion, aliens and a funny cop. Mostly, it keeps engaging you with an overarching mystery. The novel gives you a jarring view of what contact with extra-terrestrial intelligence would feel like.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Annihilation &lt;br /&gt;
Unnerving and disturbing. This book is a fictional story that reads like a non-fiction account of reality. Like a black mirror episode in a novel. It’s a quick read too.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Red Sparrow &lt;br /&gt;
A thriller that delves into Russian culture but mostly keeps you reading it at all costs. A combination of James Patterson and John Le Carré. More Patterson than Le Carré though. Also, recipes are provided at the end of every chapter.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A Brave New World &lt;br /&gt;
A terrifying view on our dystopian future. Even more striking when considered with technologies like CRISPR and stem cells. Asks many questions about human nature.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pachinko &lt;br /&gt;
A book that navigates through three generations of Korean immigrants in Japan during the Second World War. The story struck a chord with me since I come from a family of immigrants. Vividly illustrates the sacrifices that the older generation makes. Really liked this one.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A Gentleman in Moscow &lt;br /&gt;
Set in the Soviet Union in Moscow in a famous hotel. A former Count lives from middle to old-age and must raise a adopted child within the walls of the hotel. He makes the best of his experience and we see him deal with the existing and developing culture of Russia. A happy ending.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/2017/12/Age-of-Ambition.html&quot;&gt;Age of Ambition: Chasing Fortune, Truth, and Faith in the New China&lt;/a&gt; &lt;br /&gt;
A useful and striking introduction to modern day China. Illustrates the speed at which China is growing and the costs of that growth. It is long.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-last-year-&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt; last year &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Fooled by Randomness &lt;br /&gt;
This book was the catalyst for my obsession with Behavioural Economics. Nassim Nicholas Taleb effectively eliminated my trust in the global stock market and everyone who works for it. I do not, however, align with his political beliefs. Taleb lays out how we all operate under frightening amounts of randomness. Highly recommend.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Thanks, Obama &lt;br /&gt;
Being deeply immersed in US political news has made working in the White House have a magical allure. This book grounded some of my dreams in reality, but also elevated many more. Being surrounded by capable, hopeful idealists who shape the future of the world everyday will never get old.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Rosie Project &lt;br /&gt;
I started this book because Bill Gates recommended it. The whole book doesn’t seem grounded in reality, but that doesn’t make it less interesting. It speaks to how people meet each other and what influences us to start or end relationships.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Three-Body Problem &lt;br /&gt;
See above.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A Visit from the Goon Squad (twice)&lt;br /&gt;
I love this book. Describes the intertwining lives of Bennie and Sasha. The story feels melancholy the whole way through, but there are enough happy moments to pull you through.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;A Horse Walks Into a Bar &lt;br /&gt;
A dark comedy? Takes place during one evening at a comedy club. I feel like I learned something about performance by reading this book. Also hilarious at times.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Undoing Project&lt;br /&gt;
A &lt;em&gt;dense&lt;/em&gt; book. About the inception of Behavioural Economics. Follows the relationship of two academics.
 &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;American Kingpin &lt;br /&gt;
About the founder of the dark web. Draws some pretty blurry moral lines about why the main character is guilty. Recommended by Casey Neistat.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Seveneves (almost) &lt;br /&gt;
Bill Gates said he loved this book so I decided to read it. I was about three-quarters of the way through before the whole plot started getting predicable and too disheartening to follow. Interesting concept though.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;So You’ve Been Publicly Shamed &lt;br /&gt;
This book is SOOO relevant today. Describes what it feels like to be on the other side of internet outrage. How a mob mentality can lead to terrible consequences.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Swordspoint &lt;br /&gt;
As I’ve gotten older, my focus has turned away from fantasy and towards science-fiction. This book is an exception.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Sisters Brothers &lt;br /&gt;
Really good book. A Western with real cowboys and guns. Has a good moral at the end.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Psychopath Test&lt;br /&gt;
Another Jon Ronson book (SYBPS). I’ve always been fascinated by psychopaths and this book centres around what defines them as such. Do they run the world’s largest corporations? Does their existence always result in a lot of dead people?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;-probably-before-2017-&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt; probably before 2017 &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Goldfinch &lt;br /&gt;
This might be my &lt;em&gt;favourite book&lt;/em&gt;. I fell in love with every single character. About a boy and his journey through life.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Buried Giant &lt;br /&gt;
This book stayed with me. One of the most mature fantasy novels I’ve read. The authors tone is never crowded or too detailed, yet the characters are so easy to empathize with.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Revenant &lt;br /&gt;
Brutal, cunning and savage. Leo Dicaprio and bears. If you liked the movie, you’ll love the book because it’s three times as long.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Secret History &lt;br /&gt;
By the same author who wrote &lt;em&gt;the Goldfinch&lt;/em&gt; (my favourite book). “The story is an inverted detective story, not a whodunit but a &lt;em&gt;whydunit&lt;/em&gt;”. &amp;lt;— from Wikipedia
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I will finish these summaries&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;All The Light We Cannot See &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Big Short &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Flash Boys &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Boomerang &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Luminaries &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Martian &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Gone Girl &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Consider the Lobster &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the Skin of a Lion &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Game of Thrones&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bad Monkey &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Cat’s Table &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Steve Jobs &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/02/my-Book-List</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/02/my-Book-List</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>A Gentleman In Moscow</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A Gentleman in Moscow&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
by Amor Towles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-summary-&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Summary: &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Gentleman In Moscow revolves around the romantic idea of a perfect gentleman and a splendid hotel. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book begins with a description of your classic idea of a gentleman; tall, well-mannered, polite, gracious. Age: about 40? &lt;br /&gt;
After the Bolshevik revolution, he is forced to move out of his suite in the hotel in which he has been living for the past 10 years (?). The Count is relocated in a smaller room on a lower floor and is placed under house arrest. From this day forward, he cannot leave the hotel. &lt;br /&gt;
There are various descriptions of the important locations and characters in the hotel: Emile, the chef; Andrey, the maitre’d. &lt;br /&gt;
Over the course of his time at the hotel the Count meets many new people, who eventually all play an important role later in his life. &lt;br /&gt;
Foremost among those people is Nina whom the Count meets when Nina is 6? They develop a friendship and over the years become close confidants as they explore the hotel together. Nina eventually leaves the hotel with her family. &lt;br /&gt;
The Count remains at the hotel, striking up an affair with a movie star, Anna, and developing more familiar relationships with the staff of the hotel various sub-businesses; restaurant, bar, barbershop, tailor, etc. He almost commits suicide but is convinced (indirectly) by a blind man he had made friends with not to. &lt;br /&gt;
Many years later, Nina returns to the hotel with her child, Sophia, age six. Nina tells the Count that she must leave for Serbia to find her husband who has gone missing. She implores the Count to take Sophia for what she imagines will only be two or three weeks. &lt;br /&gt;
Sophia remains under the care of the Count for much longer than that. Sophia begins referring to the Count as “papa” and their relationship develops from something polite and cold to a warm and loving relationship. &lt;br /&gt;
Sophia grows into a smart, driven, beautiful young woman and eventually leaves the hotel to perform with the Moscow Orchestra (she has become an accomplished pianist). The Orchestra performs in Paris and while she is there, Sophia escapes to the American Embassy (under the specific direction of her and the Count’s plan) to meet with another one of the Count’s aquaintances become friend, Richard, who is the American Ambassador to France (?). &lt;br /&gt;
The book ends with the Count escaping the hotel after saying goodbye to all his friends there and returning to his childhood town. &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;-my-takeaways-&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt; My takeaways &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book helps the reader to appreciate the culture and history of Russia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book argues that a gentleman remains a gentleman no matter their nation of heritage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It offers an interesting perspective on the passage of time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many life lessons are delivered. This is one of the easier to quote ones:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“ The first was that if one did not master one’s circumstances, one was bound to be mastered by them; and the second was Montaigne’s maxim that the surest sign of wisdom is constant cheerfulness. ”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/a-Gentleman-In-Moscow</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/01/a-Gentleman-In-Moscow</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>thoughts on 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I don’t really know what to think about 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are a bunch of thoughts that have nothing to do with the new year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about education and what the value of a degree is, and the following seems relevant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;from-david-foster-wallaces-kenyon-college-commencement-speech&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;From David Foster Wallace’s Kenyon College Commencement Speech&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Here is the real, no bullshit value of your liberal arts education is supposed to be about: how to keep from going through your comfortable, prosperous, respectable adult life dead, unconscious, a slave to your head and to your natural default setting of being uniquely, completely, imperially alone day in and day out.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;If you worship money and things, if they are where you tap real meaning in life, then you will never have enough, never feel you have enough. It’s the truth. Worship your body and beauty and sexual allure and you will always feel ugly. And when time and age start showing, you will die a million deaths before they finally grieve you. On one level, we all know this stuff already. It’s been codified as myths, proverbs, clichés, epigrams, parables; the skeleton of every great story. The whole trick is keeping the truth up front in daily consciousness. Worship power, you will end up feeling weak and afraid, and you will need ever more power over others to numb you to your own fear. Worship your intellect, being seen as smart, you will end up feeling stupid, a fraud, always on the verge of being found out. But the insidious thing about these forms of worship is not that they’re evil or sinful, it’s that they’re unconscious. They are default settings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe that relates to my next point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;are-you-day-trading-from-seth-godins-blog&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Are you day trading? (From Seth Godin’s Blog)&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The volatility of bitcoin turns the people who own it into addicts. At any given moment, it’s up $100 or down a thousand.&lt;br /&gt;
When it’s up, you think you’re brilliant, that you somehow had something to do with it.
And when it’s down, the world is about to implode.&lt;br /&gt;
Most people don’t day trade bitcoin, but all of us day trade something. We’re hooked into something volatile, easily measured and emotional. We overdo our response to news, good or bad, and let it distract us from the long-term job of living a useful life.&lt;br /&gt;
Your SEO results, your Facebook likes, the look on your boss’s face when she gets back from a meeting–all of these things are rife with opportunities for day trading.&lt;br /&gt;
It’ll be volatile with or without your help. Better to set it aside and get back to the real work of making a difference instead. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt; This is a rant :&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The goal of a business is to make a profit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A business employs people because they do work and make the business profitable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You work towards a University degree because you will do work better and will be more attractive to businesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, all that matters is &lt;i&gt;results&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the point. Instead of proving your value through getting a degree, prove your value by getting results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get page views, get purchase orders, show your understanding of how consumers think and how to take advantage of it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are very few people who teach at Universities who have attained results. They have been taught about results, they talk about results, they think about results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But they never get results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the end of the day, the only way to absolutely prove you get results, is to get results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is why I am so unsure of this University thing. No one can prove they know how to get results by teaching. Only by doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Summary: Success in University does not directly translate to success in the real world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;creative-people-have-a-weird-job&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt;Creative people have a weird job&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you create things that &lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; think are cool, or do you create things that you think &lt;em&gt;other people&lt;/em&gt; will like. In more abstract terms, it’s the difference between staying true to yourself and selling out, right? But how do you define the line between your audience’s taste and your own. Presumably, a great creator would accumulate such a unique audience that there would be no difference between their two tastes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe it’s a matter of having a constant conversation with your audience. Each party challenging the other the create new and better things. The difference between that and losing your own say in the things you create is a blurry one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I assume the only absolute solution is to create as if your audience is irrelevant.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2018/01/thoughts-on-2017</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2018/01/thoughts-on-2017</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Breakfast at Tiffany’s</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;other than the blatant racism and subtle sexism, breakfast at tiffany’s is a film that spoke to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i haven’t had much experience with relationships, but I’ve often come across women who have an almost identical nature as audrey hepburn’s character did in the movie. free-spirited, wild, not normal. the moment things got regular, they force change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i admire that quality. at this point in my life, i loathe routine even though i live by it for the most part. as often as i can, i try to break patterns and try new things, although it is usually motivated by interest and not to force change for the sake of change.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;certainly, living the way audrey’s character does has a undeniable romantic appeal. those few people i encounter who drift into my life and astonish me only to vanish just as quickly are impossible not to admire.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the way connections are made which seem deep on one side, but superficial on another is frightening. i think its every persons fear that a friendship isn’t reciprocated with the same enthusiasm on the other end. in Aubrey’s case, it seems like that fear always comes to fruition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i guess it isn’t really her fault. the fact that her life is spent quickly building relationships then moving upwards from them may not be her fault. i think the movie makes it out to be her personality and not malicious intent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the idea of entering someone’s life, astonishing them, then leaving just as quickly is interesting to me. not only for the result on my own life, but also the lasting impression it would leave on said person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;efficient is another way to look at this. in the most optimistic sense, audrey’s character is getting everything out of a relationship in a short amount of time instead of a long one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or maybe the truth is entirely different. just because a person astonishes and surprises you, does not mean that the resulting relationship was “deep”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;presumably, a deep relationship comes from length and not intensity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;maybe that is the crux of the movie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;for her whole life, aubrey’s character lived intense and short relationships which is a admirable lifestyle as perceived from the outside. admirable because passion is more easily noticed than depth. by the end of the movie though, she decides to do the opposite and develop a long and perhaps less intense relationship.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;although, i am implying a trade-off here. passionate/exciting relationships are short and “deep” ones are long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;both of these claims are probably not entirely true.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;a deep connection can come out of a short encounter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the other side i am not so sure.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/breakfast-at-tiffany's</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/12/breakfast-at-tiffany's</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Age of Ambition</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Age of Ambition: Chasing Fortune, Truth, and Faith in the New China&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
by Evan Osnos&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-summary-&quot;&gt;&lt;u&gt; Summary: &lt;/u&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most books I read don’t stay with me for long. This one is no different.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
To combat my failing memory, I read this book on a Kindle and highlighted things so that I might remember the entire book in more detail. This post is my attempt at summarizing the book using those highlighted quotations.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
China has always been a mystery to me. The variety of culture found in the United States is so broad that I find trouble believing the one-dimensional image I have in my head of China. A country with arguably the most important economy yet I have not idea how it’s run, it’s history, the source of its growth, etc.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Also, the idea that they’re a communist country? Doesn’t the West hate Commies? Why are we okay with this?
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
This book was easy to read for a couple reasons. First, it is an interesting introduction to a country I know nothing about. It follows personal journeys of people instead of talking about numbers and economics and boring.
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
Second, it is somewhat reassuring. Here’s a fact that has consistently stuck in my mind: There are more MBAs graduating every year in China than there are undergrads graduating in the US. That’s ridiculous. Especially when there is this pessimistic outlook on the job market. China is a terrifying competitor, compounded by the fact that the US President is practically handing them the role of international leadership. 
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
That is the interesting part of this book. You are presented with their insane economic success but also China’s flaws and the negative aspect of their ridiculous growth. Notably how there entire society is more “controlled”. It often seems like a Black Mirror episode. &lt;strong&gt;China spends more money on domestic security than national defence&lt;/strong&gt;. Bus routes get rerouted so citizens won’t pass the courthouse when contested cases are in session. Creepy stuff. My optimism comes from the fact that the West has freedom and China doesn’t. That inevitably changes the culture and behaviour of people and that is clearly illustrated in the book.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It boils down to the fact that I am not jealous of anyone in China. The feeling of powerlessness against the ruling party is something I am terrified of and hope to never experience. The Politburo seems to have a much lower threshold than America for throwing a hood over someones head and locking them up forever.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It just seems like the trade off wasn’t worth it. Sure your country is arguably the largest economic superpower in the world but where is your ~culture~? It just seems bland. Relevant quote from the book:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Let your public self be like rice in a dinner: bland and inconspicuous, taking on the flavors of its surroundings while giving off no flavor of its own.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are my favourite highlights from the book, none of which are properly cited:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;She was also moved by the way he cared for his widowed father. On their second date, he proposed marriage to her on the subway.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Don’t bother looking for favoritism or nepotism here. Work hard, and your success will be clear in your results. Don’t bother kissing ass.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’d rather cry in a BMW than smile on a bicycle.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;the more violent the body contact of the sports you watch, the lower the class.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;the quantity of money passing through Macau would exceed that of Las Vegas six times over.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Chinese were found to take consistently larger risks than Americans of comparable wealth.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Li urged us to soak our feet in hot water before bed—he said it would help with jet lag&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Department had a breadth of authority over the realm of ideas in China that Anne-Marie Brady, a scholar who studied it, compared to the “Vatican’s influence over the Catholic world.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[The Department] encompassed, by one estimate, a propaganda officer for every one hundred Chinese citizens.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It was more important than ever, Party scholars pointed out, to “make their thinking conform with the dominant ideology, thereby standardizing people’s behaviour.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hu Shuli had a singular profile. She was an incurable muckraker, but had cultivated first-name familiarity with some of China’s most powerful Party leaders.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Her interviewees included a promising young cadre in city government whose openness to the free market had earned him the nickname the God of Wealth. His name was Xi Jinping, and years later he would become the president of China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Almost nine out of ten Chinese approved of the way things were going in their country—the highest share of any of the twenty-four countries surveyed that spring by the Pew Research Center. (In the United States, by comparison, just two out of ten voiced such approval.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The United States brags about its political system, but the president says one thing during the election, something else when he takes office, something else at midterm, and something else when he leaves.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Fundamentally, the culture of the Web was an almost perfect opposite of the culture of the Communist Party: Chinese leaders cherished solemnity, conformity, and secrecy; the Web sanctified informality, newness, and, above all, disclosure.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Authenticity, or the appearance of it, had become the rarest of assets in China.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When the Party praised “democracy,” it meant “democratic centralism,” the concept of debate within its own ranks, and unquestioning adherence to final decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The instinct to shield the public from unflattering facts was absurdly at odds with the openness and sophistication in other parts of Chinese life, and it seemed to cheapen what ordinary Chinese people had worked so hard to achieve.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The night before his trial, his lawyer was detained; Chen was represented by court-appointed attorneys, who called no witnesses. He was found guilty of destroying property and disrupting traffic and was sentenced to four years and three months in prison.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;By the middle of April, human rights groups were calling it the largest crackdown on expression since Tiananmen Square two decades earlier. Two hundred people had been questioned or placed under house arrest; another thirty-five were presumed to be in detention. The list included not only old-line dissidents, but also social media celebrities and journalists.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For the first time in history, the People’s Republic was spending more on domestic security than on foreign defense; it was devoting more money to policing and surveilling its own people than it was on defending against threats from abroad.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How much of the drama was light and how much was dark? How much was about opportunity and how much was about repression?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Why the most famous image from China in the past thirty years was not of its economic rise but of the man standing in front of the tank near Tiananmen Square.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;A study found that 70 percent of Chinese social media users relied on social media as their main source of news; in America, that number was 9 percent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The ugly side of China’s growth is perhaps most clearly illustrated by the train crash. Its cause was completely preventable, which only served to propel the incident to an even higher level of fame. The core problem is illustrated below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“The maintenance people weren’t familiar enough with their jobs, and they didn’t want to stop the train. They didn’t dare.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;^ China’s growth takes president over everything, even citizens own safety.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;China’s most famous public works project was an ecosystem almost perfectly hospitable to corruption—opaque, unsupervised, and overflowing with cash.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Central government was worried that if he really succeeded in giving out four hundred million in bribes he would essentially have bought a government position. That’s why he was arrested.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Public servants—officially earning twenty or thirty thousand dollars a year—became such frequent shoppers at Gucci and Louis Vuitton that high-end boutiques in Beijing ran out of stock whenever the National People’s Congress was in session.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In weak democracies, people paid their way into office by buying votes; in a state where there were no votes to buy, you paid the people who doled out the jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Corruption bruuh&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By 2012 the richest seventy members of China’s national legislature had a net worth of almost ninety billion dollars—more than ten times the combined net worth of the entire U.S. Congress.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Bo Xilai looked like a movie star.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Scandal was becoming the backbeat to China’s rise.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Oven if local bureaucrats were corrupt, its top leaders so exemplified wisdom, justice, and meritocracy that dissent and direct elections were superfluous and obsolete.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wealth was hard for the Party to explain, so it decided not to try: within twenty-four hours, the government blocked the Bloomberg website—it would stay blocked in China for the foreseeable future—and&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;It would cost the company millions in lost sales and advertising.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“He and his family can’t stay in China. It’s no longer safe,” she said. “Something will happen. It will look like an accident. Nobody will know what happened. He’ll just be found dead.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The New York Times relied on corporate records to calculate that in the years that Prime Minister Wen Jiabao was in office, his family amassed assets worth $2.7 billion.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“When the rules favor the rule-makers, they are applied; when they do not, they are ignored.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inequality index:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;(An independent calculation put the figure at 0.61, higher than the level in Zimbabwe.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;People had a surprisingly high tolerance for the rise of the plutocracy. What they resented were the obstacles that prevented them from joining it:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In all, authorities executed at least fourteen yuan billionaires in the span of eight years, on charges ranging from pyramid schemes to murder for hire.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In relation to FOXCON and the suicide nets, etc:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Outsiders were quick to imagine a sweatshop, but this explanation was not quite right.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;All websites are not to repost the news headlined, “UN Releases World Happiness Report, and China Ranks No. 112.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Foshan is a market town, the home of enormous open-air emporiums, one after another: Iron and Steel World and Flower and Plant World and Children’s Clothing Town, which sells enough clothes each year to dress every kid in America, twice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Instantly, the story of the seventeen passersby began to spread across China, and it provoked a surge of self-recrimination. The writer Zhang Lijia asked, “How can we possibly win respect and play the role of a world leader if this is a nation with 1.4 billion&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In the years of the boom, people had picked up &lt;strong&gt;more reasons to fear the law than to trust it.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;How could China ever hope to invent the next big thing, the next Facebook, if it didn’t dare to let its people use this one?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A terrifying illustration of the governments control. Not quite blatant oppression, but a more quiet insidious suppression.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The city diverted bus routes to bypass the courthouse.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Racism:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In Beijing, some shopkeepers hung signs in their windows like this one, in English, at a restaurant: THIS SHOP DOES NOT RECEIVE THE JAPANESE, THE PHILIPPINES, THE VIETNAMESE AND DOG. In this&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;When Zhai Xiaobing, a man who worked at an investment fund in Beijing, tweeted a geeky joke that compared the meeting to a new apocalypse movie, he was arrested and held for three weeks.
^ Three weeks for  tweet???&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The windows of public buses were taped shut. The city banned pleasure boats from the lakes,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;the only Tibetans at the Great Hall were members of the official Tibetan delegation, who brought news that Lhasa, their capital, had been voted “the happiest city in China”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;conducted a “Chinese Dream” survey, asking whether people supported one-party rule and believed in socialism, 80 percent of the three thousand respondents replied “no” to both questions,&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/12/Age-of-Ambition</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/12/Age-of-Ambition</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
