<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>kahvi's blog</title>
    <description>I create here sometimes. And rarely captalize.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 14:16:08 -0800</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 14:16:08 -0800</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.4.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>intro</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve come to realize that I am not educated enough about most subjects for anyone to take my opinion seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All I can offer is my perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog is not to educate or to persuade. Only to share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether my thoughts influence opinions or not is completely relative to the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally, if the &lt;em&gt;facts&lt;/em&gt; presented in any of these post are inaccurate, please send me an email.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be clear: My opinion on most issues shouldn’t be taken seriously.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/intro</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/intro</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>interesting</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;p-people-repeatedly-make-decisions-that-undermine-their-own-long-term-well-being&quot;&gt;P: People repeatedly make decisions that undermine their own long term well being.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;s-give-people-the-satisfaction-they-need-in-the-short-term-and-the-outcomes-that-want-in-the-long-term&quot;&gt;S: Give people the satisfaction they need in the short term &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; the outcomes that want in the long term.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Human don’t make good decisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Health
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Stop smoking&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Exercise more&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Education
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Study better&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Teach better&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Learn better&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Personal Finance
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Save more money&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Nudge Unit in the UK government.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;800&quot; height=&quot;400&quot; src=&quot;https://docs.google.com/spreadsheets/d/e/2PACX-1vQbhGJ1vWhHEqiSP5GWtoDDi-hoBd5OhuGNu7grNfqrNTimkB7VsohD0Ucckkvu2fyW0MrlLvQJhdBu/pubhtml?gid=1770440070&amp;amp;single=true&amp;amp;widget=true&amp;amp;headers=false&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Leading People:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Danny Kahneman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amos Tversky&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Richard Thaler&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nassim Taleb&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/interesting!</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/interesting!</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>why keep talking?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two questions that I don’t know the answer to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why do we keep theorizing about why the 2016 election turned out the way it did?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why am I so much more involved in the US political system than my own?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;1&quot;&gt;1.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Annoyance. Being virtually forced to follow the 2016 election. Entertaining at first, then annoying, then dreadful. Elections are always a pain. This one was different. Never has something been so publicized. I endured. Kept watching. Kept rolling my eyes. Knowing he could never win.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then he won.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now everyone theorizes why.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sexism?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Racism?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The establishment?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two party system?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Populism?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Angry middle class?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Political incorrectness?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Television presence?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Media attention?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do too. It was the media. That’s what I think.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Main point:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;we-will-never-know-why-trump-won-the-2016-election&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;We will never know why Trump won the 2016 election.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why keep talking?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;2&quot;&gt;2.&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pay more attention to US politics than I do Canadian politics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naming the speaker of the house, senate majority and minority leader, secretary of state, defence, energy, education and the vice-president is easy, yet naming anyone other than Justin Trudeau in the Canadian executive branch is impossible. Is it even called an executive branch here? I don’t know.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Justifying my seemingly extreme interest in US politics is difficult. Am I engaged because these policies and changes in leadership could affect my own life? No. Although they may have a vague effect on me, it is unreasonable to think that anything other than a declaration of war by the US would be directly relevant to me. 
Importantly, that is not to say that US politics are not relevant to me &lt;em&gt;at all&lt;/em&gt;, the point is that there are &lt;em&gt;many&lt;/em&gt; more relevant things I could be paying attention to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The real reason why I pay an unreasonable amount of attention to US politics is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;b&gt;It’s entertainment that makes you feel smart.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is why:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Almost all of what I pay attention to will not affect me.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I rarely learn more than the headline, and almost never delve into the actually policy at hand.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;More often than not, I do not learn anything from the news.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I learn on a week to week basis is basically the equivalent of a Stephen Colbert monologue. I remember the headlines, forget the policy and get some entertainment out of the process.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Question: Why don’t I follow Canadian politics just as attentively?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answer: The US has a sophisticated media infrastructure built around making politics entertaining.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before it was the president’s &lt;em&gt;intent&lt;/em&gt; is to be entertaining, the media made politics entertaining on its own. Remember Obama’s Khaki suit? Or the birth certificate?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why doesn’t Canada have the same entertainment infrastructure? Where is our Stephen Colbert monologue making fun of Justin Trudeau’s socks or something?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reasons why there isn’t entertainment focused around Canadian politics:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The events happening aren’t as exciting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;People in Canada are not interested in politics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;There are less people in general, so less potential viewers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidetone: The first reason might cause the following one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A misconception is that an audience for Canadian politics doesn’t exist. If the way the news is presented is entertaining, an audience will develop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example #1: me. Why am I consuming so much US political news? Because of the way it is presented. There is almost no logical reason why I should be as engaged as I am in the Virginia Governor’s Race, but I’m refreshing the polls right now all the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forms of media about politics I consume:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;podcasts&quot;&gt;Podcasts&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pod Save America&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The Ezra Klein Show&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;This American Life&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Revisionist History&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;On The Media&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Stay Tuned&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;youtube&quot;&gt;Youtube&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Phillip Defranco&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;John Oliver&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Stephen Colbert&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Samantha Bee&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Seth Myers&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;h3 id=&quot;news&quot;&gt;News&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Reddit&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Vox&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;the Economist&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Five Thirty Eight&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wall Street Journal&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be continued,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;or deleted???&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 02 Nov 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/11/why-keep-talking</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/11/why-keep-talking</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>on the timelessness of skateboarding</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;this is just here to remind me to write about this&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/on-the-timeless-beauty-of-skateboarding</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/10/on-the-timeless-beauty-of-skateboarding</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>on vlogging and its dangerous applications</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;sorry, this is just here to remind me to write about this&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/10/on-vlogging-and-its-dangerous-implications</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/10/on-vlogging-and-its-dangerous-implications</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>internet dialogues</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Don’t try to argue with someone on the internet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sorry im gonna finish this someday&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 03 Sep 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/09/internet-dialogues</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/09/internet-dialogues</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>halifax</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried to start this a few times.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I'm going to Victoria in the fall.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Please forgive the forthcoming John-Green-teenage-romance-movie language.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know how else to say this: You are my closest group of friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I can’t pretend like I’m certain about the decision I’m making. There’s so much uncertainty in my life right now and nothing really seems absolute about my future. I just know that the program in Victoria is better for me, and I feel like I'll do well there.
&lt;p&gt;For me, this past year was the most defining period of my life and I am so thankful to you for that. &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past year was so much more about people than it was about school, and I’m only realizing that now.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I miss you guys and I will continue to miss you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I know that you all will get somewhere great in life.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You all deserve so much. You are all so kind. Please realize that you can help sarcastic, boring pricks like me and open them up to things beyond what they can learn on their own.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You guys changed me and I owe you for that.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sidenote: Also I'm getting a tattoo and I need your input. It's to remember Halifax. I'm thinking like just the letters &quot;UKC&quot; in like handwriting or like the geographical coordinates of Alex Hall or maybe like an anchor?? idk but plz text me before I make a bad decision&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 24 Aug 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/08/halifax</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/08/halifax</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>stock market</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;this post is incomplete&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
After spending 18 years of my life idolizing rich investement bankers on Wall Street, I have come to a brutal realization:&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Most investing is gambling.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;I realized this after reading Nassim Taleb’s book, Fooled by Randomness. To summarize, Taleb proves that behaviours like hindsight bias and pattern-seeking are widely prevalent in today’s society, especially in the investment banking sector. Often, bankers are victim to completely random occurences in the market, yet attribute them to “skill” and “foresight”. I wrote a bit about this:
  &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;A striking example of this behavior is the justification for the start of World War 1. Clearly, the assassination of Franz Ferdinand and the escalating tension and militarization in various countries might predict international conflict. The ensuing World War seems to have been inevitable - after the events have transpired. This is an example of hindsight bias. As Niall Ferguson, a professor of history at Harvard, makes clear in his paper &lt;em&gt;The international bond market between the 1848 revolution and the outbreak of the First World War&lt;/em&gt;, war bond prices were steady. The world had not noticed these so-called significant events. &lt;b&gt;If these hints towards the upcoming conflict were as clear as we now make them out to be, why did the price of war bonds not rise?&lt;/b&gt; Was there a sudden, universal lack of desire to make profit? or were the events we speak of today not obvious at all. Clearly, the latter is more in line with human nature. We feel the need to justify events after the fact in order to reassure ourselves that we will see it coming next time.
    &lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;matthew counts as more evidence for this point
  &lt;img src=&quot;http://kahvipatel.com/Media/nobody2.gif&quot; alt=&quot;Small example image&quot; title=&quot;nobody2&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;You can never win against a computer.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It take a human about 300-400 milliseconds to blink. Currently, it takes &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.investopedia.com/articles/investing/091615/world-high-frequency-algorithmic-trading.asp&quot;&gt;High Frequency Trading Firms&lt;/a&gt; (basically computers that trade stocks) &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.technologyreview.com/s/602135/high-frequency-trading-is-nearing-the-ultimate-speed-limit/&quot;&gt;85 nanoseconds&lt;/a&gt; to execute a trade. To put that into perspective, in the time it take you to blink your eye, &lt;em&gt;one&lt;/em&gt; HFT computer could execute 3.5 million trades. Basically, computers are just alot faster that you are.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unpredictable in the short term, predictable in the long term: The only certain way to make money in the stock market is over time.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;http://awealthofcommonsense.com/wp-content/uploads/2015/11/SPX-Time-Frames.png&quot; alt=&quot;Small example image&quot; title=&quot;investing chart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
^if you invest in an S&amp;amp;P 500 ETF, you can basically flip a coin to see whether you will make money tommorow. In a decade though, you have a much higher chance of profit.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
okay, here’s a research paper
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Kahvi Patel&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Research Paper&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Tutorial 9&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;April 17&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt;, 2017&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Tutor: S. Boos&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;In the early 20&lt;sup&gt;th&lt;/sup&gt; century, the separation between scientific and non-scientific theories was vague. The most practical way to distinguish a theory as scientific was to determine whether it was known a posteriori; relied on an empirical method. This meant that astrology, given its vast amounts of observed information, qualified as a scientific theory. In 1919, Karl Popper sought to contrive an alternative separation. Falsifiability was the philosophical term he coined. With this theory, Popper set the groundwork for the modern scientific method and, simultaneously, addressed the problem of induction that had troubled Hume and many other philosophers before him. Popper’s theory of Falsification, however, not only has its roots in philosophy, but in human nature. As has been the case throughout history, human nature is more prone towards what Popper distinguished as “pseudo-scientific” theories rather than “scientific” ones. Our inherent desires are what make Popper’s theory of Falsification especially relevant; Demarcation is a tool to fight against our own misleading natural instincts. In order to repress this widespread malpractice, we must employ tactics of doubt exemplified by philosophers like Descartes and Socrates in order to enforce a more logical, and therefore more productive, general consciousness. As Popper originally described in his theory, falsification, rather than confirmation, must be what we seek in order to prove our own theories.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;For Popper, the reason for distinguishing between theories was not for lack of truth; “it was not my doubting the truth of those other…theories which bothered me, but something else” (Popper 32). Neither was it because of the different nature of some theories or the variability in accuracy they provided. In fact, what bothered Popper were the incessant “confirming instances” relating to the “pseudo-scientific theories” in question. Freud’s theory of psychoanalysis, for example, was supported repeatedly by whatever the psychologist theorized. In other words, every event confirmed the theory. This practice has a flaw.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;I may illustrate this by two very different examples of human behavior: that of a man who pushes a child into the water with the intention of drowning it; and that of a man who sacrifices his life in an attempt to save the child. Each of these two cases can be explained with equal ease in Freudian and in Adlerian terms. According to Freud the first man suffered from repression (say, of some component of his Oedipus complex), while the second man had achieved sublimation. According to Adler the first man suffered fro feelings of inferiority (producing perhaps the need to prove to himself that he dared to commit some crime), and so did the second man (whose need was to prove to himself that he dared to rescue the child). (Popper 35)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;This situation demonstrates the ambiguity of Freud’s (and Adler’s) theory. The result, no matter how unexpected or crazy, can always be justified. This method was in direct contrast to another Popper had witnessed; Einstein’s theory of gravitation. Whereas Freud’s theory relied on explanation, Einstein’s relied on prediction. More specifically, one sought confirmation, the other sought falsification. Alarmingly though, both relied on empirical evidence and the method of induction, thus classifying them both, for now, as scientific theories. Importantly, Popper did not attempt to discredit the validity of Freud’s theory, although he may have done so unconsciously. His intention was merely to distinguish it. The significance of this separation cannot be understated. As history progressed, a scientific method was developed around Popper’s falsifiability and a distinguishable separation began to emerge between science and others things.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;More than just a method for distinction between theories, Falsification has significance in human behavior. In general, humans are programmed to ignore events that do not agree with their beliefs and pay attentions to ones that do. This behavior is called confirmation bias. Unfortunately, it has been proven to exist throughout many studies, the most famous of which is the Wason Selection Task.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;He presented subjects with the three-number sequence 2, 4, 6, and asked them to try to guess the rule generating it. Their method of guessing was to produce other three-number sequences, to which the experimenter would respond “yes” or “no” depending on whether the new sequences were consistent with the rule. Once confident with their answers, the subjects would formulate the rule. The correct rule was “numbers in ascending order,” nothing more. Very few subjects discovered it because in order to do so they had to offer a series in descending order (that the experimenter would say “no” to). (Taleb 123)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;This experiment demonstrates our inherent instinct to always seek confirmation for our own hypothesis, or theories, instead or trying to discredit them. Once the subjects had formulated a rule, their only intention became trying to find a pattern that fit it instead of trying to supply a series that was inconsistent with their hypothesis. Our natural human behavior compels us to seek confirmation. The parallels here are widespread. Today, most people gather their information (and biases) from the news. And there is more news today than ever before. The constant news cycle compounds biases. People have access to countless sources of evidence, or “number series”, which they use to confirm their own opinions. It becomes much more difficult to attempt to disprove your own opinion.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;A most poignant example of this behavior of confirmation bias is the political polarization that currently exists in the United States: both sides seek confirmation for their own theories, never falsification. Popper’s Demarcation seems to work against human instinct. For instance, Freud’s theory of psychoanalysis is more easily understandable than Einstein’s theory of gravity and thus more attractive. This inherent preference leads to many human patterns of behavior, such as illusion of control and hindsight bias. When a need to explain something arises, we are predisposed to justify our theory by seeking confirmation instead of testing it. &lt;b&gt;A striking example of this behavior is the justification for the start of World War 1. Clearly, the assassination of Franz Ferdinand and the escalating tension and militarization in various countries might predict international conflict. The ensuing World War seems to have been inevitable - after the events have transpired. This is an example of hindsight bias which generates pseudo-scientific theories. As Niall Ferguson, a professor of history at Harvard, makes clear in his paper &lt;em&gt;The international bond market between the 1848 revolution and the outbreak of the First World War&lt;/em&gt;, the world had not noticed these so-called significant events, as evidenced by the flat lining of war bond prices. If these hints towards the upcoming conflict were as clear as we now make them out to be, why did the price of war bonds not rise? Was there a sudden, universal lack of desire to make profit? or were the events we speak of today not obvious at all. Clearly, the latter is more in line with human nature. The pseudo-scientific theory suggests that the war started because of an episode of tension and militarization. This is an example of seeking confirmation and hindsight bias. We feel the need to justify events after the fact in order to reassure ourselves that we will see it coming next time.&lt;/b&gt; More often than not, however, our theories for the cause of past events are vulnerable to falsification. Until those theories in question can withstand falsification, this practice of explanation is useless.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Our constant desire to fabricate an illusion of control leads us to justify theories in unreliable ways. When theories are not tested with falsification, they can lead us to misleading conclusions or a false sense of security. In 470 BC, Socrates exposed society’s wrongful act of gathering, spreading and reciting knowledge that had illogical grounds. In what we now call “Socratic Dialogue”, Socrates reduced his subject’s opinions to a single thesis which was often illogical. Through this, he proved the Delphi’s prophecy true: he was, in fact, “the wisest of men”. This title, however, did not originate from vast education or far-reaching experience.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;I am wiser than this man; it is likely that neither of us knows anything worthwhile, but he thinks he knows something when he does not, whereas when I do not know, neither do I think I know; so I am likely to be wiser than he to this small extent, that I do not think I know what I do not know. (Plato 3)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Socrates was merely the only man who knew the extent of his own ignorance. Today, we encounter a similar situation. Many of our generally accepted theories and personal opinions are illogical and/or justified by a flawed method. More importantly though, the vast majority of society &lt;em&gt;does not realize&lt;/em&gt; this. Descartes provides another apt exemplar. His doubt, though undoubtedly extreme, was important to build a foundation of truth upon which the rest of his beliefs were founded.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;&lt;a style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot; name=&quot;GoBack&quot;&gt;
&lt;/a&gt;It is as though they [my beliefs] had a right to a place in my belief-system as a result of long occupation and the law of custom. These habitual opinions of mine are indeed highly probable; although they are in a sense doubtful, as I have shown, it is more reasonable to believe than to deny them. But if I go on viewing them in that light I shall never get out of the habit of confidently assenting to them. To conquer that habit, therefore, I had better switch right around and pretend (for a while) that these former opinions of mine are utterly false and imaginary. I shall do this until I have something to counter-balance the weight of old opinion, and the distorting influence of habit no longer prevents me from judging correctly. (Descartes 2)&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;The important parallel here is doubt. To doubt one’s own belief is the most basic and true form of falsification. We must draw from influences of the past to create a better future. We must take advice from Socrates and Descartes and question our own theories and opinions in order to arrive at the roots of our beliefs. We must acknowledge our own ignorance in order to take the next step towards progress.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Popper’s philosophy was originally meant to distinguish scientific theories. His philosophy of Demarcation, however, went beyond science, and addressed two methods of thinking. Unfortunately for humanity, we are prone to the less reliable mode of thinking: one that seeks confirmation. This behavior has led to a worrying trend in human history. By analyzing the past and present, we may understand how hindsight bias and the illusion of control reveal themselves in society and how they are the result of instinctual human behavior. With the problem assessed and recognized, we may understand it and endeavor to solve it. Turning to philosophers of the past, such as Descartes and Socrates, helps us recognize the underlying theme of doubt in their work and leads us to an apt solution. Doubt is perhaps the truest form of falsification and should be practiced by individuals today in order to help justify beliefs. The practice of seeking to falsify one’s own beliefs takes courage and determination but is ultimately the path towards a more reliable future. Unless we begin challenging our beliefs, instead of seeking confirmation of them, moral progress will slow. If we begin using Popper’s method in our lives, diversity of opinion and success will be the result.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Works Cited&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Popper, Karl. &lt;em&gt;Conjectures and Refutations&lt;/em&gt;. Basic Books, 1962.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Nicholas Taleb, Nassim. &lt;em&gt;The Black Swan: The Impact of the Highly Improbable.&lt;/em&gt; Random House, 2007.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Ferguson, Niall. “Political risk and the international bond market between the 1848 revolution and the outbreak of the First World War.” &lt;em&gt;Economic History Review&lt;/em&gt;, Vol 29, no. 1, February 2006.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Plato. &lt;em&gt;Apology&lt;/em&gt;. translated by G.M.A. Grube, Hackett Publishing Company, 2000.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;span style=&quot;color: #000000;&quot;&gt;Descartes, Renee. &lt;em&gt;Meditations on First Philosophy&lt;/em&gt;. translated by Jonathan F. Bennett, Cambridge University Press, 1996.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
inspired by Nassim Nicholas Taleb and &lt;a href=&quot;http://jamesclear.com/book-summaries/fooled-by-randomness&quot;&gt;Fooled by Randomness&lt;/a&gt; (great read)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jul 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/07/stock-market</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/07/stock-market</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>the hair question</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Current State: Long hair&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pros:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Looks better than short hair IMO&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Takes less time to prepare (Effort to Look ratio is great)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Less money spent on haircuts (more efficient for financials)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Looks slightly better with hats&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Compliments facial hair&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cons:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;When let down, it is impossible to manage&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Gets greasy quite quickly (Discourages working out)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Is sometimes uncomfortable when in bad bun&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Takes a long time to dry (Discourages working out)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Extra weight?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Cumbersome with hoods&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Discourages lying down&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Looks less professional/trustworthy&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alternative: Short hair&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pros:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Easier to manage&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Would be more comfortable and usable&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Less weight?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Less time to dry (encourages working out)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Looks more professional/trustworthy&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Could add height&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cons:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Doesn’t look as good IMO&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Requires more haircuts&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;More time to prepare in the morning&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Doesn’t really compliment the facial hair&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;oct 2017 update: I have short hair now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/05/the-hair-question</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/05/the-hair-question</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>drafts</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;take two deep breaths before reading or else youll probably faint &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tinder bios&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll fuck you harder than trump is fucking middle america&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When I’m high I turn into Jaden Smiths twitter account&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’ll pay more attention to you than dj khaled does to his garden&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The day Trump got elected I laughed so hard my left lung came out.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I lift often. Lift people out of poverty that is. I volunteer bi weekly at an local community center.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re ever beside me on a plane, i’ll give you the armrest&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tweets&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Appointing Rick perry to head the EPA is like appointing ryan lochte to teach calculus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why are the blinkers on cars always off tempo like fuck just sync up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yes sir it is completely fine that you are reclining your seat this early into the flight please carry on&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;gets cramp walking away from the cafeteria&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I wish i could talk with one percent of the confidence that migos have when they rap gibberish&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sometimes you have great professors and sometimes you have a textbook that managed to learn how to speak&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Trusting Putin is like trusting that Jimmy Fallons laugh is actually real&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;if is takes me three weeks to learn how to recline the chairs in Killam then yeah I’m probably gonna fail this exam&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2017 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/02/drafts</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/02/drafts</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
